<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Bubblehouse</title>
        <description>Bubblehouse - Phil Christensen</description>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2014-04-08T20:57:06-04:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2014-04-08T20:57:06-04:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>Jekyll Introduction</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;This Jekyll introduction will outline specifically what Jekyll is and why you would want to use it. Directly following the intro we’ll learn exactly &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; Jekyll does what it does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;overview&quot;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what_is_jekyll&quot;&gt;What is Jekyll?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a parsing engine bundled as a ruby gem used to build static websites from dynamic components such as templates, partials, liquid code, markdown, etc. Jekyll is known as “a simple, blog aware, static site generator”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;examples&quot;&gt;Examples&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is created with Jekyll. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Sites&quot;&gt;Other Jekyll websites&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what_does_jekyll_do&quot;&gt;What does Jekyll Do?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a ruby gem you install on your local system. Once there you can call &lt;code&gt;jekyll --server&lt;/code&gt; on a directory and provided that directory is setup in a way jekyll expects, it will do magic stuff like parse markdown/textile files, compute categories, tags, permalinks, and construct your pages from layout templates and partials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once parsed, Jekyll stores the result in a self-contained static &lt;code&gt;_site&lt;/code&gt; folder. The intention here is that you can serve all contents in this folder statically from a plain static web-server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can think of Jekyll as a normalish dynamic blog but rather than parsing content, templates, and tags on each request, Jekyll does this once &lt;em&gt;beforehand&lt;/em&gt; and caches the &lt;em&gt;entire website&lt;/em&gt; in a folder for serving statically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jekyll_is_not_blogging_software&quot;&gt;Jekyll is Not Blogging Software&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll is a parsing engine.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll does not come with any content nor does it have any templates or design elements. This is a common source of confusion when getting started. Jekyll does not come with anything you actually use or see on your website - you have to make it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why_should_i_care&quot;&gt;Why Should I Care?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll is very minimalistic and very efficient. The most important thing to realize about Jekyll is that it creates a static representation of your website requiring only a static web-server. Traditional dynamic blogs like Wordpress require a database and server-side code. Heavily trafficked dynamic blogs must employ a caching layer that ultimately performs the same job Jekyll sets out to do; serve static content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore if you like to keep things simple and you prefer the command-line over an admin panel UI then give Jekyll a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Developers like Jekyll because we can write content like we write code:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ability to write content in markdown or textile in your favorite text-editor.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ability to write and preview your content via localhost.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No internet connection required.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ability to publish via git.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ability to host your blog on a static web-server.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Ability to host freely on GitHub Pages.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;No database required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how_jekyll_works&quot;&gt;How Jekyll Works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a complete but concise outline of exactly how Jekyll works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be aware that core concepts are introduced in rapid succession without code examples. This information is not intended to specifically teach you how to do anything, rather it is intended to give you the &lt;em&gt;full picture&lt;/em&gt; relative to what is going on in Jekyll-world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learning these core concepts should help you avoid common frustrations and ultimately help you better understand the code examples contained throughout Jekyll-Bootstrap.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial_setup&quot;&gt;Initial Setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&quot;/index.html#start-now&quot;&gt;installing jekyll&lt;/a&gt; you’ll need to format your website directory in a way jekyll expects. Jekyll-bootstrap conveniently provides the base directory format.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the_jekyll_application_base_format&quot;&gt;The Jekyll Application Base Format&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll expects your website directory to be laid out like so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.
|-- _config.yml
|-- _includes
|-- _layouts
|   |-- default.html
|   |-- post.html
|-- _posts
|   |-- 2011-10-25-open-source-is-good.markdown
|   |-- 2011-04-26-hello-world.markdown
|-- _site
|-- index.html
|-- assets
    |-- css
        |-- style.css
    |-- javascripts&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_config.yml&lt;/strong&gt; Stores configuration data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_includes&lt;/strong&gt; This folder is for partial views.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_layouts&lt;/strong&gt; This folder is for the main templates your content will be inserted into. You can have different layouts for different pages or page sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_posts&lt;/strong&gt; This folder contains your dynamic content/posts. the naming format is required to be &lt;code&gt;@YEAR-MONTH-DATE-title.MARKUP@&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;_site&lt;/strong&gt; This is where the generated site will be placed once Jekyll is done transforming it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;assets&lt;/strong&gt; This folder is not part of the standard jekyll structure. The assets folder represents &lt;em&gt;any generic&lt;/em&gt; folder you happen to create in your root directory. Directories and files not properly formatted for jekyll will be left untouched for you to serve normally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(read more: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Usage&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Usage&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;jekyll_configuration&quot;&gt;Jekyll Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll supports various configuration options that are fully outlined here: (&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Configuration&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Configuration&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;content_in_jekyll&quot;&gt;Content in Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content in Jekyll is either a post or a page. These content “objects” get inserted into one or more templates to build the final output for its respective static-page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;posts_and_pages&quot;&gt;Posts and Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both posts and pages should be written in markdown, textile, or HTML and may also contain Liquid templating syntax. Both posts and pages can have meta-data assigned on a per-page basis such as title, url path, as well as arbitrary custom meta-data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working_with_posts&quot;&gt;Working With Posts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a Post&lt;/strong&gt; Posts are created by properly formatting a file and placing it the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting&lt;/strong&gt; A post must have a valid filename in the form &lt;code&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DATE-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; and be placed in the &lt;code&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. If the data format is invalid Jekyll will not recognize the file as a post. The date and title are automatically parsed from the filename of the post file. Additionally, each file must have &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/YAML-Front-Matter&quot;&gt;YAML Front-Matter&lt;/a&gt; prepended to its content. YAML Front-Matter is a valid YAML syntax specifying meta-data for the given file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Order&lt;/strong&gt; Ordering is an important part of Jekyll but it is hard to specify a custom ordering strategy. Only reverse chronological and chronological ordering is supported in Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the date is hard-coded into the filename format, to change the order, you must change the dates in the filenames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tags&lt;/strong&gt; Posts can have tags associated with them as part of their meta-data. Tags may be placed on posts by providing them in the post’s YAML front matter. You have access to the post-specific tags in the templates. These tags also get added to the sitewide collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categories&lt;/strong&gt; Posts may be categorized by providing one or more categories in the YAML front matter. Categories offer more significance over tags in that they can be reflected in the URL path to the given post. Note categories in Jekyll work in a specific way. If you define more than one category you are defining a category hierarchy “set”. Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;title :  Hello World
categories : [lessons, beginner]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This defines the category hierarchy “lessons/beginner”. Note this is &lt;em&gt;one category&lt;/em&gt; node in Jekyll. You won’t find “lessons” and “beginner” as two separate categories unless you define them elsewhere as singular categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;working_with_pages&quot;&gt;Working With Pages&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating a Page&lt;/strong&gt; Pages are created by properly formatting a file and placing it anywhere in the root directory or subdirectories that do &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; start with an underscore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting&lt;/strong&gt; In order to register as a Jekyll page the file must contain &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/YAML-Front-Matter&quot;&gt;YAML Front-Matter&lt;/a&gt;. Registering a page means 1) that Jekyll will process the page and 2) that the page object will be available in the &lt;code&gt;site.pages&lt;/code&gt; array for inclusion into your templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Categories and Tags&lt;/strong&gt; Pages do not compute categories nor tags so defining them will have no effect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sub-Directories&lt;/strong&gt; If pages are defined in sub-directories, the path to the page will be reflected in the url. Example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.
|-- people
    |-- bob
        |-- essay.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This page will be available at &lt;code&gt;http://yourdomain.com/people/bob/essay.html&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Pages&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;index.html&lt;/strong&gt; You will always want to define the root index.html page as this will display on your root URL.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;404.html&lt;/strong&gt; Create a root 404.html page and GitHub Pages will serve it as your 404 response.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sitemap.html&lt;/strong&gt; Generating a sitemap is good practice for SEO.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;about.html&lt;/strong&gt; A nice about page is easy to do and gives the human perspective to your website.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;templates_in_jekyll&quot;&gt;Templates in Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Templates are used to contain a page’s or post’s content. All templates have access to a global site object variable: &lt;code&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; as well as a page object variable: &lt;code&gt;page&lt;/code&gt;. The site variable holds all accessible content and metadata relative to the site. The page variable holds accessible data for the given page or post being rendered at that point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a Template&lt;/strong&gt; Templates are created by properly formatting a file and placing it in the &lt;code&gt;_layouts&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formatting&lt;/strong&gt; Templates should be coded in HTML and contain YAML Front Matter. All templates can contain Liquid code to work with your site’s data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rending Page/Post Content in a Template&lt;/strong&gt; There is a special variable in all templates named : &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt;. The &lt;code&gt;content&lt;/code&gt; variable holds the page/post content including any sub-template content previously defined. Render the content variable wherever you want your main content to be injected into your template:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...
&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div id=&quot;sidebar&quot;&amp;gt; ... &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;div id=&quot;main&quot;&amp;gt;
    &amp;#123;{content}&amp;#125;
  &amp;lt;/div&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;/body&amp;gt;
...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;subtemplates&quot;&gt;Sub-Templates&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sub-templates are exactly templates with the only difference being they define another “root” layout/template within their YAML Front Matter. This essentially means a template will render inside of another template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;includes&quot;&gt;Includes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jekyll you can define include files by placing them in the &lt;code&gt;_includes&lt;/code&gt; folder. Includes are NOT templates, rather they are just code snippets that get included into templates. In this way, you can treat the code inside includes as if it was native to the parent template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any valid template code may be used in includes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using_liquid_for_templating&quot;&gt;Using Liquid for Templating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Templating is perhaps the most confusing and frustrating part of Jekyll. This is mainly due to the fact that Jekyll templates must use the Liquid Templating Language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what_is_liquid&quot;&gt;What is Liquid?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Shopify/liquid&quot;&gt;Liquid&lt;/a&gt; is a secure templating language developed by &lt;a href=&quot;http://shopify.com&quot;&gt;Shopify&lt;/a&gt;. Liquid is designed for end-users to be able to execute logic within template files without imposing any security risk on the hosting server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll uses Liquid to generate the post content within the final page layout structure and as the primary interface for working with your site and post/page data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;why_do_we_have_to_use_liquid&quot;&gt;Why Do We Have to Use Liquid?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GitHub uses Jekyll to power &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/a&gt;. GitHub cannot afford to run arbitrary code on their servers so they lock developers down via Liquid.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;liquid_is_not_programmerfriendly&quot;&gt;Liquid is Not Programmer-Friendly.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The short story is liquid is not real code and its not intended to execute real code. The point being you can’t do jackshit in liquid that hasn’t been allowed explicitly by the implementation. What’s more you can only access data-structures that have been explicitly passed to the template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Jekyll’s case it is not possible to alter what is passed to Liquid without hacking the gem or running custom plugins. Both of which cannot be supported by GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a programmer - this is very frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But rather than look a gift horse in the mouth we are going to suck it up and view it as an opportunity to work around limitations and adopt client-side solutions when possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aside&lt;/strong&gt; My personal stance is to not invest time trying to hack liquid. It’s really unnecessary &lt;em&gt;from a programmer’s&lt;/em&gt; perspective. That is to say if you have the ability to run custom plugins (i.e. run arbitrary ruby code) you are better off sticking with ruby. Toward that end I’ve built &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/plusjade/mustache-with-jekyll&quot;&gt;Mustache-with-Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;static_assets&quot;&gt;Static Assets&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static assets are any file in the root or non-underscored subfolders that are not pages. That is they have no valid YAML Front Matter and are thus not treated as Jekyll Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Static assets should be used for images, css, and javascript files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how_jekyll_parses_files&quot;&gt;How Jekyll Parses Files&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember Jekyll is a processing engine. There are two main types of parsing in Jekyll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content parsing.&lt;/strong&gt; This is done with textile or markdown.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template parsing.&lt;/strong&gt; This is done with the liquid templating language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thus there are two main types of file formats needed for this parsing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post and Page files.&lt;/strong&gt; All content in Jekyll is either a post or a page so valid posts and pages are parsed with markdown or textile.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Template files.&lt;/strong&gt; These files go in &lt;code&gt;_layouts&lt;/code&gt; folder and contain your blogs &lt;strong&gt;templates&lt;/strong&gt;. They should be made in HTML with the help of Liquid syntax. Since include files are simply injected into templates they are essentially parsed as if they were native to the template.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Arbitrary files and folders.&lt;/strong&gt; Files that &lt;em&gt;are not&lt;/em&gt; valid pages are treated as static content and pass through Jekyll untouched and reside on your blog in the exact structure and format they originally existed in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;formatting_files_for_parsing&quot;&gt;Formatting Files for Parsing.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve outlined the need for valid formatting using &lt;strong&gt;YAML Front Matter&lt;/strong&gt;. Templates, posts, and pages all need to provide valid YAML Front Matter even if the Matter is empty. This is the only way Jekyll knows you want the file processed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;YAML Front Matter must be prepended to the top of template/post/page files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;layout: post
category : pages
tags : [how-to, jekyll]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;... contents ...&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three hyphens on a new line start the Front-Matter block and three hyphens on a new line end the block. The data inside the block must be valid YAML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Configuration parameters for YAML Front-Matter is outlined here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/YAML-Front-Matter&quot;&gt;A comprehensive explanation of YAML Front Matter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;defining_layouts_for_posts_and_templates_parsing&quot;&gt;Defining Layouts for Posts and Templates Parsing.&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;layout&lt;/code&gt; parameter in the YAML Front Matter defines the template file for which the given post or template should be injected into. If a template file specifies its own layout, it is effectively being used as a &lt;code&gt;sub-template.&lt;/code&gt; That is to say loading a post file into a template file that refers to another template file with work in the way you’d expect; as a nested sub-template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how_jekyll_generates_the_final_static_files&quot;&gt;How Jekyll Generates the Final Static Files.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Jekyll’s job is to generate a static representation of your website. The following is an outline of how that’s done:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll collects data.&lt;/strong&gt; Jekyll scans the posts directory and collects all posts files as post objects. It then scans the layout assets and collects those and finally scans other directories in search of pages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll computes data.&lt;/strong&gt; Jekyll takes these objects, computes metadata (permalinks, tags, categories, titles, dates) from them and constructs one big &lt;code&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; object that holds all the posts, pages, layouts, and respective metadata. At this stage your site is one big computed ruby object.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll liquifies posts and templates.&lt;/strong&gt; Next jekyll loops through each post file and converts (through markdown or textile) and &lt;strong&gt;liquifies&lt;/strong&gt; the post inside of its respective layout(s). Once the post is parsed and liquified inside the the proper layout structure, the layout itself is “liquified”. &lt;strong&gt;Liquification&lt;/strong&gt; is defined as follows: Jekyll initiates a Liquid template, and passes a simpler hash representation of the ruby site object as well as a simpler hash representation of the ruby post object. These simplified data structures are what you have access to in the templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jekyll generates output.&lt;/strong&gt; Finally the liquid templates are “rendered”, thereby processing any liquid syntax provided in the templates and saving the final, static representation of the file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes.&lt;/strong&gt; Because Jekyll computes the entire site in one fell swoop, each template is given access to a global &lt;code&gt;site&lt;/code&gt; hash that contains useful data. It is this data that you’ll iterate through and format using the Liquid tags and filters in order to render it onto a given page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, in Jekyll you are an end-user. Your API has only two components:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The manner in which you setup your directory.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The liquid syntax and variables passed into the liquid templates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the data objects available to you in the templates via Liquid are outlined in the &lt;strong&gt;API Section&lt;/strong&gt; of Jekyll-Bootstrap. You can also read the original documentation here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Template-Data&quot;&gt;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/wiki/Template-Data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this paints a clearer picture of what Jekyll is doing and why it works the way it does. As noted, our main programming constraint is the fact that our API is limited to what is accessible via Liquid and Liquid only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll-bootstrap is intended to provide helper methods and strategies aimed at making it more intuitive and easier to work with Jekyll =)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thank you&lt;/strong&gt; for reading this far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;next_steps&quot;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or jump right into &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Usage&lt;/a&gt; if you’d like.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/lessons/2011/12/29/jekyll-introduction</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/lessons/2011/12/29/jekyll-introduction</guid>
                <pubDate>2011-12-29T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Neat Color-Coded `svn status` Wrapper Script</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I found a handy script online that colorized the output of SVN status. It worked pretty well, but needed a little polish and a couple of tweaks to make it use more common Python idioms. Also, I fixed ANSI word-wrapping issues, created a configurable tab expansion feature (for better code alignment), added the ‘colorizedSubcommands’ sequence so that only applicable commands get colorized, and fixed subprocess calls so that piping through less will work (for example, try &lt;tt&gt;svn-color diff | less -r&lt;/tt&gt; to see colorized diff output).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you find my modifications useful. You can modify the colors used by looking up the ANSI color codes for your preferred color scheme and editing the ‘statusColors’ dictionary. Here’s a useful reference for ANSI color values:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-tip-prompt/colortable.gif'&gt;http://www.ibm.com/developerworks/linux/library/l-tip-prompt/colortable.gif&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’ve posted the code on &lt;a href='http://snipplr.com'&gt;snipplr&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s also posted below after the break.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;div class='snipplr_embed' id='snipplr_embed_28748'&gt;&lt;a href='http://snipplr.com/view/28748/colorcoded-svn-status-v3/'&gt;code snippet - color-coded `svn status` (v3)&lt;/a&gt; on snipplr&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script src='http://snipplr.com/js/embed.js' type='text/javascript'&gt;&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;&lt;script src='http://snipplr.com/json/28748' type='text/javascript'&gt;&lt;![CDATA[]]&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/chl0ag9u/dw5pea==/ymfzaa==/c3zu/2010/02/22/neat-color-coded-svn-status-wrapper-script</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/chl0ag9u/dw5pea==/ymfzaa==/c3zu/2010/02/22/neat-color-coded-svn-status-wrapper-script</guid>
                <pubDate>2010-02-22T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>modu version 1.0 released!!!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;After two years of continual development, documentation, and production use, I've arbitrarily decided to tag modu with a version 1.0, as well as make a formal release.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;modu is released under the &lt;a href='http://modu.bubblehouse.org/trac/browser/trunk/LICENSE'&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license. For installation instructions, see &lt;a href='http://modu.bubblehouse.org/trac/wiki/Installation'&gt;Installation&lt;/a&gt; or the included &lt;a href='http://modu.bubblehouse.org/trac/browser/tags/modu-1.0.2/INSTALL'&gt;INSTALL&lt;/a&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tar package&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTP&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href='http://modu.bubblehouse.org/releases/modu-1.0.2.tar.gz#egg=modu-1.0.2'&gt;modu-1.0.2.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;tt&gt;md5sum: 33242ce8c2a3c6292aca46ee563e431b &lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;p&gt;A great deal of changes have occurred over the last few weeks as I've removed tons of cruft and dependencies from the main codebase, and in particular completed the transition to setuptools-based installation, and the setuptools Resource API to handle assets more effectively. Additionally, the Cheetah integration now caches templates in memory, which should allow for use of template #cache directives, although I haven't really tried this yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Dependencies:&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Python 2.5&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Twisted 9&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Cheetah 2.4.1&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;MySQLdb 1.2.3c1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;There is currently experimental support included for CherryTemplates and ZPTPages template engines, as well as the PostgreSQL and SQLite databases.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Latest Stable Release 1.0.2&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;1.0.2 is a new stable maintenance release, released on February 07, 2010 at 11.18PM. It contains a number of bug fixes and minor enhancements. See the &lt;a class='source' href='/trac/browser/tags/modu-1.0.0/ChangeLog'&gt;ChangeLog&lt;/a&gt;  for details.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;div&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Tar package&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTP&lt;/strong&gt;: 			&lt;a href='http://modu.bubblehouse.org/releases/modu-1.0.2.tar.gz#egg=modu-1.0.2'&gt;modu-1.0.2.tar.gz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;sub&gt;&lt;tt&gt;md5sum: 33242ce8c2a3c6292aca46ee563e431b &lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/sub&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;Binary Distribution&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Automatically install and compile modu and related dependencies:
    &lt;pre&gt;
# easy_install modu&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h4&gt;SVN Tag&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;To check out a snapshot of the source code from SVN HEAD, use the following incantation:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
svn co http://svn.bubblehouse.org/modu/tags/modu-1.0.2&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/chjvz3jhbw1pbmc=/dhdpc3rlza==/bw9kdq==/c29mdhdhcmu=/cmvszwfzzq==/2010/02/09/modu-version-1-0-released</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/chjvz3jhbw1pbmc=/dhdpc3rlza==/bw9kdq==/c29mdhdhcmu=/cmvszwfzzq==/2010/02/09/modu-version-1-0-released</guid>
                <pubDate>2010-02-09T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>MySQLs mangled syntax handling and INNER JOINs</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;As my DBA skills have progressed over the years, I’m always impressed and upset to see the extent to which MySQL has allowed me to use terrible syntax generally not accepted by standards-compliant SQL servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A recent one really blew me away, because it exposed a lack of understanding on my part about how to understand the syntax of JOIN commands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is how I always built nested JOIN queries. The premise is that semantically you are always selecting from a single table; the use of the INNER JOIN statement is treated like a function that returns a compound table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style='text-align:left;color:#ffffff; background-color:#000000; border:solid black 1px; padding:0.5em 1em 0.5em 1em; overflow:auto;font-size:small; font-family:monospace; '&gt;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; r.name &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;role&lt;/span&gt;, p.name &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; permission&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;role&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;INNER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;JOIN&lt;/span&gt; (role_permission rp&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;INNER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;JOIN&lt;/span&gt; permission p &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt; (rp.permission_id = p.&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;))&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt; (rp.role_id = r.&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;ORDER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;BY&lt;/span&gt; r.name, p.name&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when trying to run this same snippet against an SQLite3 database, I would continue to get a &lt;span class='error'&gt;no such column: p.name&lt;/span&gt; error. After some research, I found the preferable way to do nested joins is much simpler, if less semantically pleasing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style='text-align:left;color:#ffffff; background-color:#000000; border:solid black 1px; padding:0.5em 1em 0.5em 1em; overflow:auto;font-size:small; font-family:monospace; '&gt;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;SELECT&lt;/span&gt; r.name &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;role&lt;/span&gt;, p.name &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;AS&lt;/span&gt; permission&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;FROM&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;role&lt;/span&gt; r&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;INNER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;JOIN&lt;/span&gt; role_permission rp &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt; rp.role_id = r.&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;INNER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;JOIN&lt;/span&gt; permission p &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;ON&lt;/span&gt; rp.permission_id = p.&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;id&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;ORDER&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style='color:#dfb098;'&gt;BY&lt;/span&gt; r.name, p.name&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This works for me properly in both SQLite and MySQL. I’m curious what it was that made me ever start writing nested JOINs in the former method; it was fairly error-prone due to missing parenthesis, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/y29kaw5n/bxlzcww=/chjvz3jhbw1pbmc=/c3fsaxrl/2010/02/02/mysqls-mangled-syntax-handling-and-inner-joins</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/y29kaw5n/bxlzcww=/chjvz3jhbw1pbmc=/c3fsaxrl/2010/02/02/mysqls-mangled-syntax-handling-and-inner-joins</guid>
                <pubDate>2010-02-02T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>bass notes for seaflux tunes</title>
                <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;bass_notes&quot;&gt;bass notes&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;underworld&quot;&gt;underworld&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;opening riff: key of bbm, repeats 3x guitar alone, then distorted w/drums&amp;amp;bass, then with octave verse: bbm, a (4x) chorus: power chords; bb, gb, f (4x)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;repeat verse and chorus, pause after 2nd chorus&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;guitar plays outro riff twice, then drums&amp;amp;bass join in&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;outro riff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;g---------------------------------------------------
d-----------7-6---8-7-6-------------------7-6---8---
a-----6-7-8-----7-------7-8-6-------6-7-8-----7-----
e---7-------------------------7---7-----------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;breakbeat jam over outro riff starts quiet, gets louder and more intense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 repeats of outro riff signals the end&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;interlude&quot;&gt;interlude&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hits: c g eb c verse: gm bb c eb chorus: power chords; c eb bb g&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hits verse (2x, instrumental)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hits verse (2x, w/lyrics) verse (1x, instrumental) verse (2x, w/lyrics) chorus (2x)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hits verse (2x, w/lyrics) verse (1x, instrumental) verse (2x, w/lyrics) chorus (2x)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sustained g power chord for one bar, then outro&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;outro:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;a section                      3x
g-||---------------------------||-----------------
d-||*-------------3-----------*||-----------------
a-||*-------3-4-5---5-4-3-----*||-----------------
e-||--3-5-6---------------6-5--||-3-5-6-3-5-6-3---

b section                                  4x
g-||---------------------------------------||-----
d-||*-------------------------------------*||-----
a-||*-------------3---5-6-3---3-5-3-------*||-----
e-||--3-5-6-3-5-6-----------6-------6-5-4--||-3---

c section (repeat until you don't ;-)
g-----------||---------------||
d-----------||*-------------*||
a-----------||*-----5-7-5---*||
e-----0-----||--5-7-------7--||&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jam forever, no specific ending, maybe will jam into another tune.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/2010/01/13/bass-notes-for-seaflux-tunes</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/2010/01/13/bass-notes-for-seaflux-tunes</guid>
                <pubDate>2010-01-13T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Compiling PHP 5.2.10 on Mac OS X 10.5.7</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
MACOSX_DEPLOYMENT_TARGET=10.5 CFLAGS=&amp;quot;-arch ppc -g -Os -pipe -no-cpp-precomp&amp;quot; CCFLAGS=&amp;quot;-arch ppc -g -Os -pipe&amp;quot; CXXFLAGS=&amp;quot;-arch ppc -g -Os -pipe&amp;quot; LDFLAGS=&amp;quot;-arch ppc -bind_at_load&amp;quot; ./configure –prefix=/usr –mandir=/usr/share/man –infodir=/usr/share/info –with-apxs2=/usr/sbin/apxs –with-ldap=/usr –with-kerberos=/usr –enable-cli –with-zlib-dir=/usr –enable-exif –enable-mbstring –enable-mbregex –enable-sockets –with-iodbc=/usr –with-config-file-path=/etc –sysconfdir=/private/etc –with-iconv=shared,/opt/local –with-openssl=shared,/opt/local –with-xmlrpc –with-xsl=/usr –with-gd –with-mysqli=/usr/local/mysql/bin/mysql_config –with-png-dir=/opt/local
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/2009/06/30/compiling-php-5-2-10-on-mac-os-x-10-5-7</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/2009/06/30/compiling-php-5-2-10-on-mac-os-x-10-5-7</guid>
                <pubDate>2009-06-30T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Camp MMW Rocked My Face Off</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been two days since I returned from Camp MMW, and I still feel like I haven’t returned to reality yet. The experience was kind of like joining Fight Club — everything at work has had the volume turned down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I was first accepted, I wasn’t really sure I was going to go. I had been amassing a decent-sized pile of debt, and I wasn’t sure if it would be wise to get that much deeper, but conversations with friends and family convinced me that this was a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity, and besides, “when was the last time you took a vacation?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, the days leading up to camp had been filled with a surprisingly large amount of musical activity; rehearsals with two bands, various excellent shows in the city, and of course my trip to the Rothbury Festival in Michigan. Seeing MMW there really got me pumped for camp, and I could really tell they were really on fire this summer. All this excellent music had me well-primed for the events to come…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the day finally came, I packed my stuff (including far too many guitars and effects), and made a short jaunt up to the Catskills. The drive was beautiful, of course, but I had some anxiety about the trip. I had practically no idea what to expect; although we’d been given a tentative schedule, I had endless questions about how things would work. However, I made a promise to myself not to let my usual social anxiety interfere with getting the most out of this experience. I was determined to talk to as many people as possible, and planned to stick myself into any jam situation I could, even if I ended up making an ass out of myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;arriving_at_camp&quot;&gt;Arriving at Camp&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I arrived, I could immediately feel a sort of energy in the air. I could tell that all the campers were feeling the same way I was; a bit nervous, but also thrilled and determined to meet everyone — and get down to some musical business. I met my roommates Pravin and Jamie and we immediately got along, so one weight had already been lifted off my shoulders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By this time there was already music drifting from afar, so I followed my ears to the Barn where a jam session had already coalesced. I stuck to my guns and took the first opportunity to jump up there and groove out with the other campers. Camp had officially begun!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening meet and greet and subsequent dinner gave us all a chance to congregate and learn about each other, where we were all from, and the influences that brought us to camp. Everyone seemed to be in a state of disbelief, all the while being absolutely pumped to be there. Even though we all came from different places and musical backgrounds, the connecting thread of a love of MMW gave us all some common ground to stand on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_band&quot;&gt;The Band&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before camp, I had seen MMW play maybe 8-9 times, and had amassed a collection of bootlegged recordings that I always made sure got rotated into my daily iPod shuffle. Still, I knew practically nothing about them, other than the usual stuff you can glean from Wikipedia or Allmusic. In fact, I didn’t even know what John Medeski or Chris Wood’s voices even sounded like, and knew nothing about Billy except that he was “Billy Martin, I play the drums”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening MMW master class immediately gave us an idea of the offstage chemistry of the group. It seems so clichéd to say it, but you instantly knew that although these guys were clearly brilliant musicians, they were still “regular guys.” Obviously, you can’t really get to know someone in five days, but I feel like I now have a bit of an understanding of the character types that make up MMW.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, John Medeski is like a mad scientist. Not the evil megalomaniac kind, but more of a “Absent-Minded Professor” type. Although there was endless information that he wanted to convey, he did it all in a manner that was immediately accessible to me. I was most pleased to learn what would become a recurring theme over the week, that although he had an amazing grasp of theory and a technical mastery of his instrument, that wasn’t what was most important to him, but simply a tool to help him reach improvisational heights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Wood had a similar skill at conveying complex ideas, but it was contained in a different personality. The best way to describe it is like an older student helping out a younger one. I remember when I first was learning guitar, and meeting older guys who had been playing much longer than I had, but who were eager to help me out with tips and techniques to get the most out of my playing. Chris’ style was much like this, although combined with a sort of professorial style that made advanced concepts seem really clear and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billy Martin…hmm…well, I’m going to quote Frank Zappa when talking about Pierre Boulez, and say that Billy is “serious as cancer.” Okay, I know that sounds extreme, but over the weekend I was just struck by the energy that Billy exuded; it wasn’t that I was intimidated by him, &lt;em&gt;per se&lt;/em&gt;, but any time I interacted with him I felt like I wanted to prove that I was just as serious about music as he was. ;-) I appreciated his candor and his vast knowledge of rhythm and world influences, but was also pleased to discover that he wasn’t really into reading or writing western notation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_campers&quot;&gt;The Campers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Possibly one of the most shocking things about this whole experience was how completely awesome all the other campers were. Perhaps it was because we were all so thankful to be there, but everyone I met was totally cool and unique in various ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a great mix of instruments, lots of drummers and bassists, and a reasonable number of guitar and keys players. Due to sheer numbers, we all had to be mindful of giving others time to play and not monopolizing jam sessions, which were basically self-governed. Pretty much everybody was good about this, and those that weren’t were really just so excited to be there, I could hardly get mad at them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I got a little inside info about how the sleeping arrangements were figured out. The ‘official’ word was that they were most concerned about the younger campers getting wild, so they put them all with some of the older campers in hopes of “keeping them in check.” However, considering that they put most of the 22-35-year-olds in the lodge that was across the street, secluded from the main camp area, suggests that they might have been more interested in keeping us from corrupting the nation’s youth. It was probably a wise decision. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;master_classes&quot;&gt;Master Classes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every day one of the band members or guest speakers would present a master class to all the campers, going into detail about their influences and ideas about music, different ways they would practice, songwriting techniques, and general life lessons for musicians.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John’s was the first one (apart from the full band master class on opening day), and was focused largely on the metaphysical aspects of music, with a separate emphasis on how musical ideas can be found in practically everything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billy was up next, and got really into some of his world influences. It was interesting to compare his teaching style to John’s; although with Medeski I could pretty easily take notes just from what he was saying, Billy’s style was a lot more informal. I realized that I just needed to listen and try to derive my own “knowledge nuggets” from what he was discussing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Wood’s master class was probably my favorite. He began with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ted.com/index.php/talks/jill_bolte_taylor_s_powerful_stroke_of_insight.html&quot;&gt;an amazing video&lt;/a&gt; of Dr. Jill Taylor’s experiences during a stroke in the left side of her brain. It was a great introduction to a talk about right-left brain functionality and how this affects you as a player of improvised music.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the time we arrived, there had been a schedule change, and there was to be a “special guest” giving a master class over at the performance space. Rumors circulated all week about who it might be, but by Saturday afternoon we had our answer when John Scofield got in line for lunch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately Sco wasn’t able to stay for the whole day, so they merged his master class with a MSMW performance. Hearing them all jam together and open up with “A Go-Go” was an amazing experience, though, and was making the face cramping I had (from excessive smiling) that much worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sco took a few minutes in the middle of their performance to take questions from the audience, but I think audience and band alike just wanted more jamming. They brought it back with a killer Little Walter, and finished up with a Miles Behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;ensembles&quot;&gt;Ensembles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest aspects of camp was the ensemble groups. We were split into three groups, and each would have a sort of rehearsal with each of the band members over three days. Although there was still a lot of us in each group, this gave us all a chance to play, and also made things more productive, since each band member acted as a conductor to keep things fresh and interesting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first ensemble meeting was with John Medeski. This was my first exposure to Billy’s ‘riddims’; after being taught these clave rhythms through group clapping, we all had a chance to go onstage and play them on our own instruments. This featured one of the more significant highlights of the week for me, when I (and about five other students) got to jam along on these riddims with John wailing away on the Wurlitzer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next ensemble I had was with Chris Wood. In this case we were split into three groups, and while two groups would go off with Chris to work on more riddim exercises, the rest were left with 20 minutes to create an arrangement of a field recording/spiritual, illustrating how you can find compositional ideas in many different places. Our group was actually the last to go up, so we had the fortune of learning from everyone else’s mistakes, and got to use the remaining time to talk with Chris about arranging techniques.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Billy’s ensemble was more freeform than the others, which was a nice contrast. He built small ensembles out of the players in the class, and conducted them through various free playing exercises. There was a focus on playing ‘gestures’, a concept first discussed by Steve Bernstein during his master class, and which became another recurring meme throughout the week. Our goal was to play a small cell of music or sound that we felt represented us each as players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another highlight for me was during Billy’s ensemble where we got to play a new MMW composition that he had created to be released on their next album. Camper Larry Legend was on the ball, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://vids.myspace.com/index.cfm?fuseaction=vids.individual&amp;amp;videoid=40547289&quot;&gt;got a great video of us working on this tune&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;workshops&quot;&gt;Workshops&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshops were a bit more hands-on than the master classes, and also happened simultaneously, so you had to pick one of three or four different ones to go see. The first one I attended was Marc Ribot’s “Extended Techniques for Guitar and Alternate Improvisation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought I was familiar with Marc’s work beforehand; I knew him as MMW’s ‘preferred’ guitarist (I think Sco is evaluated separately), but I had little to no understanding of the level of his expertise. In addition to being a respectable classical or jazz player, Marc’s blues chops are amazing, and his devotion to experimentation and “avant rock” is pretty much unparalleled. I thoroughly enjoyed this class, which featured a six- or seven- guitar choir conducted by Marc using hand signals he developed for use with Modified Cobra.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next up for me was Medeski’s workshop, “The ‘Ins’ of ‘Taking It Out’.” John talked about an approach to extended harmony that I hadn’t encountered before. It ran along with one of the themes of the camp, which was the importance of learning theoretical concepts in a way that allows you to use them naturally, without thinking. One approach focused on learning the sounds of the more ‘out’ chord combinations by stacking triads against each scale degree, while another gave us a foundational understanding of how the ‘rules of improvisational harmony’ (the ones that say you “always” play a Dorian scale over a minor 7th chord) were created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was hard to pick between Billy and Chris’ workshops for the last one, but I went with the second of Chris’ “Making Music On a Fret Board” classes. Here I learned a number of new exercises to help improve my fretboard fluidity as well as improve my note reading (an area in which I continue to be sorely lacking). Since this class my practice sessions have been far more productive, but I was glad to hear again the emphasis on forgetting that stuff when you’re actually in performance mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;jam_sessions&quot;&gt;Jam Sessions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, the jam sessions were my favorite part of camp. It seemed like a lot of the players there were either disinterested or intimidated by the jam session environment. I heard some people say they didn’t like the “competitive” nature of the sessions, which was weird to me. These sessions felt like a bunch of close friends jamming compared to the cut-throat attitudes I’ve encountered in other scenarios. Remind me to tell you a story sometime about friends of mine getting berated onstage at this jazz club in NYC called “Smoke”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, at first, it was a widely discussed problem that most of the jams were leaning towards one-chord funk and blues jams. It shouldn’t have been surprising; since there were so many players, most jamming situations involved a large number of musicians. This is not an easy thing to deal with, and it took awhile for this stuff to settle down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I mentioned previously, all the campers tried to be good about giving other people the chance to play. During these first few jams, however, it was clear that you had to be reasonably assertive, and willing to walk right up ask to hop on for awhile. This might have been part of the problem for a lot of people; no amount of passive-aggression was going to get you a chance to play. Of course, as we got to know each other, even this lightened up, and people were calling out for anyone who wanted to take over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple days, things had really come along. Far more exploration was happening, and people were really being conscious of how much space they were taking up in the mix. My only criticism in the end was that since everyone wanted to play so bad, and usually had to wait for awhile to get a chance, no one had any interest in trying out a new set of changes, or having any kind of pre-jam “planning” discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, it was a very educational experience for me. For one thing, when I play improvised music with people, I always seem to end up being the leader. I’ve theorized several reasons for this, from basic personality types to the fact that I play guitar (which as a soprano instrument really just ends up cutting through everything). Still, at Camp MMW, getting the group to follow you was a strictly meritocratic process, since they weren’t going to take up that groove you hinted at or accent that rhythm you played unless they really liked what you were doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At various points, people would try to take on the role of conductor. This was a good idea, but a few conductors didn’t really understand the nature of what they were trying to do. A popular comment was that doing this was a lot like “herding cats”; it was best not to expect miracles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;performances&quot;&gt;Performances&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The highlight of nearly every day, however, was the nightly performance. Now, I’ve seen MMW play some small venues, but the performance space at camp can only be described as a ‘cabin’. The stage was so small, John couldn’t even have his piano there, but they raged it up every night without fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were some special sessions; one night started with Steve Bernstein putting together a huge ensemble of students. This was pretty good, but I was glad to see Steve and MMW take the stage for a closing set. After a whole day of jam sessions and thinking about jamming, my standards had been raised pretty high, and only MMW could cap the day off properly ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marc Ribot’s set with MMW was probably my favorite (if you believe it’s possible to pick a ‘favorite’ out of four nights of mind-blowing performances). The thing that’s craziest about hearing him play with the band is that he fits in so seamlessly. When he wasn’t intentionally standing out (like during a solo in a raging blues number they did), and assuming you weren’t watching closely, it would sometimes be hard to differentiate between his lines and some of Medeski’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last night was billed in the schedule as “Students featured into MMW performance.” Everyone was wondering how this was going to work out — the band had been so good at not ‘playing favorites’ that it seemed impossible for them to just select a few people. In the end, things were set up like a larger version of Billy’s ensemble, where the band members conducted the group through a hour-and-a-half long collaboration. People who wanted to play just sat at the front, and would be rotated in and out by the band.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had come prepared to play, but in the end I screwed myself by trying to be too clever. MMW had pretty much told us that the focus was going to be on the students for this show, but that they would “try to interact” with us when possible. I wanted to listen for a bit, and see how things were working up there, but I also figured that my best bet for getting to jam with one of them on stage was to wait a little while, and try to get on towards the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I made my way to the front, and after a few minutes, John called me up. I walked up there, but by that time, something had changed, and he said something to me that I couldn’t hear, but it seemed like they weren’t ready yet. I sat down to wait it out, and little by little the players were replaced by the members of the band, except for two guitar players (who, of course, had no one to replace them).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was sure they were going to nod these guys off any minute now, so I figured it would be inappropriate to tap in (one of the guys was barely playing at all, and I could have snuck up to him easily). I kept waiting, but before I realized it, two other guitar players had tapped in, and joined the band in one last raging blues number. I had missed my chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, the replacements were pretty great, and after they had brought the blues jam to a close, MMW took the stage for one last trio performance, and brought the house down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Incidentally, up until this point people had been pretty restrained during the performances, with everybody sitting in a bunch of folding chairs in front of the stage, and those of us freaks who wanted to dance towards the back. This time, however, the freaks took over, and pulled people up out of their seats, pushed the chairs out of the way, and everybody started to &lt;em&gt;get down&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It still wasn’t over, of course, and we closed the night out with a number of great jams at the cafe, and a certain amount of &lt;em&gt;responsible debauchery&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the_aftermath&quot;&gt;The Aftermath&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last day of camp was pretty anti-climactic. We all got to sleep in a little more, and the morning was filled with the swapping of contact info, and plans of what to do with ourselves when we got home, now that we’d become “enlightened.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They always say about vacations, that you should be excited to leave and glad to get home. This was definitely the deal for me; after a week of high-intensity musical immersion, I needed out. I was glad that I was one of the fortunate ones who had a fairly quick drive home; as soon as I arrived, I called up the band and arranged a rehearsal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Playing with the “old crew” was exactly what I needed to bring me back down to earth (or somewhere close to it), and I started to be able to process all the stuff that had happened. There was so much to think about, even to this day I’m still having epiphanies about things we talked about, or observations I made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I felt like while a learned a huge amount at Camp MMW, the biggest impact it made on me was showing me that I was on the right track with regards to improvisation. At so many different times I would hear something that I had been thinking about, or discussing with the band, and I would have my original thoughts validated and clarified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when I see really amazing musicians, I go home with this feeling of “why do I bother even playing at all?”, and want to pack my guitar away and give up. This time, however, despite getting an even clearer picture of how amazing MMW is, I went home thinking “okay, I understand what I have to do. it’s hard, but at least I &lt;em&gt;understand&lt;/em&gt; it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now let’s see how long this feeling lasts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/z3vpdgfy/y2ftcg1tdw==/2008/08/12/camp-mmw-rocked-my-face-off</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/z3vpdgfy/y2ftcg1tdw==/2008/08/12/camp-mmw-rocked-my-face-off</guid>
                <pubDate>2008-08-12T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>japh</title>
                <description>&lt;pre&gt;
$Z=sub{for($Z=0;$Z&amp;lt;@_;$Z++){$z=oct(&amp;quot;$_[$Z++]&amp;quot;).&amp;quot;$_[$Z++]&amp;quot;.$_[$Z];for($W=0;
$W&amp;lt;length($z);$W++){($n,$N)=split(m--,substr($z,$W,2));$W++;$X=int($n);
push(@V,split(m++,${N}x${X}));}}for($W=0;$W&amp;lt;@V/3;$W++){$_=chr(int($V[$W].
$V[$W+055].$V[$W+0x5A]));$_=~tr,a-zA-Z,n-za-mN-ZA-M,;print $_;}};$Z-&amp;gt;(10016,0x460,
4120,6046,0x1810,3110,15706,0x83e,1130,2437,0xb5e,2110,2447,0x456,1213,6050,0x456,
3411,2613,0x840,1321,1763,0x7db,1910,2151,0x584,1312,1771,0x715,1714,2130,0x77a,
2112,3256,0x4ba,1411,7032,0x5ef,1718,2142,0x6af,1812,2442,0x6b0,1417);
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/cgvyba==/amfwaa==/2008/03/17/japh</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/cgvyba==/amfwaa==/2008/03/17/japh</guid>
                <pubDate>2008-03-17T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>64-bit MySQL and DBD::mysql Woes</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I was attempting to install DBD::mysql today, and I ran into a fiendishly difficult problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve installed the mysql drivers for Perl countless times, but this time for some reason, I was getting the following error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ool-4577f347:~/.cpan/build/DBD-mysql-4.004 root# make cc -c -I/Library/Perl/5.8.6/darwin-thread-multi-2level/auto/DBI -I/usr/local/mysql/include -Os -arch ppc64 -fno-common -DDBD_MYSQL_INSERT_ID_IS_GOOD -g -g -pipe -fno-common -DPERL_DARWIN -no-cpp-precomp -fno-strict-aliasing -I/usr/local/include -Os -DVERSION=\&amp;quot;4.004\&amp;quot; -DXS_VERSION=\&amp;quot;4.004\&amp;quot; &amp;quot;-I/System/Library/Perl/5.8.6/darwin-thread-multi-2level/CORE&amp;quot; dbdimp.c dbdimp.c: In function ‘mysql_dr_connect’: dbdimp.c:1565: error: ‘ulong’ undeclared (first use in this function) dbdimp.c:1565: error: (Each undeclared identifier is reported only once dbdimp.c:1565: error: for each function it appears in.) dbdimp.c:1565: error: parse error before numeric constant dbdimp.c:1567: error: parse error before numeric constant dbdimp.c:1681: error: parse error before numeric constant make: *** dbdimp.o Error 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found a tip over at &lt;a href='http://fuel.stuffo.info/blog/archives/11'&gt;http://fuel.stuffo.info/blog/archives/11&lt;/a&gt;, and added a line to /usr/local/mysql/include/mysql_com.h:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;typedef unsigned long ulong;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once I did that, I got through that error, but I had problems at the linking stage, getting an error like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;/usr/bin/ld: truncated or malformed archive: /usr/local/mysql/lib/libmysqlclient.a (ranlib structures in table of contents extends past the end of the table of contents, can’t load from it)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, this is a problem with the 64-bit version of MySQL 5.0 (thanks to &lt;a href='http://devel.webwork.rochester.edu/twiki/bin/view/Webwork/TigerInstall'&gt;http://devel.webwork.rochester.edu/twiki/bin/view/Webwork/TigerInstall&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I reinstalled &lt;a href='http://dev.mysql.com/downloads/mysql/5.0.html'&gt;32-bit MySQL&lt;/a&gt;, the DBD::mysql package compiled and installed without a problem. In fact, I didn’t even have to add that line to &lt;tt&gt;mysql_com.h&lt;/tt&gt;. However, all was not well, because for some reason, whenever code tried to &lt;strong&gt;use&lt;/strong&gt; this module, (either ‘make test’ or actual code), I got the cryptic error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;install_driver(mysql) failed: Can’t load ‘/Users/phil/.cpan/build/DBD-mysql-4.004-bd2Pvk/blib/arch/auto/DBD/mysql/mysql.bundle’ for module DBD::mysql: dlopen(/Users/phil/.cpan/build/DBD-mysql-4.004-bd2Pvk/blib/arch/auto/DBD/mysql/mysql.bundle, 2): Library not loaded: /usr/local/mysql/lib/mysql/libmysqlclient.15.dylib Referenced from: /Users/phil/.cpan/build/DBD-mysql-4.004-bd2Pvk/blib/arch/auto/DBD/mysql/mysql.bundle Reason: image not found at /System/Library/Perl/5.8.6/darwin-thread-multi-2level/DynaLoader.pm line 230. at (eval 3) line 3&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried a million things to solve this, thinking it was some leftover residue from my previous MySQL install. Unfortunately, even after a clean reinstall of MySQL, the same error was occurring. I looked more closely at the error, hoping to divine some deeper meaning, when it hit me. I knew the library existed, but I couldn’t figure out why the perl library loader couldn’t find it. Closer examination revealed that for some reason the library path had an extra component in it. The solution was a simple symlink:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ln -s /usr/local/mysql/lib /usr/local/mysql/lib/mysql
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, ridiculous, I know. But it fixed the problem, and everything is working fine now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/dw5pea==/bxlzcww=/y29tcglsaw5n/2007/06/03/64-bit-mysql-and-dbdmysql-woes</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/dw5pea==/bxlzcww=/y29tcglsaw5n/2007/06/03/64-bit-mysql-and-dbdmysql-woes</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-06-03T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Fun with Xargs on Mac OS X</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is something I wrote over at &lt;a href='http://docforge.com'&gt;DocForge&lt;/a&gt;, but I&amp;#8217;m keeping it here for posterity. You never know what those crazy wiki-ers might do with it over there &lt;tt&gt;;-)&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve got a directory full of eBooks in the godawful Microsoft .lit format. I had marked with the Finder labels the ones I&amp;#8217;ve already read, and wanted to convert all the ones I hadn&amp;#8217;t read yet into a readable format.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After using the Spotlight UNIX tools and applying liberal amounts of command-line trickery, the end result was a rather beautiful pipeline, if I do say so myself.
&lt;!--break--&gt;
First, I used the &lt;tt&gt;mdfind&lt;/tt&gt; command to filter all the Items that had the red label. We&amp;#8217;re going to query the &lt;tt&gt;kMDItemFSLabel&lt;/tt&gt; properties; the red label has a value of &lt;tt&gt;6&lt;/tt&gt; (I found this out by using &lt;tt&gt;mdls&lt;/tt&gt; on a file with the desired label).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since I only want to search a particular directory, I use the &lt;tt&gt;-onlyin&lt;/tt&gt; switch to limit the query:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre class='bash'&gt;mdfind -onlyin /Users/phil/Desktop/books/ &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;&amp;quot;kMDItemFSLabel&amp;nbsp;!= 6&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre&gt;/Users/phil/Desktop/books/one.lit
/Users/phil/Desktop/books/two.lit
/Users/phil/Desktop/books/other.rtf
/Users/phil/Desktop/books/three.lit
/Users/phil/Desktop/books/something.html
...
...&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of those aren&amp;#8217;t .lit files, so I&amp;#8217;ll just use &lt;tt&gt;grep&lt;/tt&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre class='bash'&gt;mdfind -onlyin /Users/phil/Desktop/books/ &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;&amp;quot;kMDItemFSLabel&amp;nbsp;!= 6&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; | grep &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;&amp;quot;.lit&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre&gt;/Users/phil/Desktop/books/one.lit
/Users/phil/Desktop/books/two.lit
/Users/phil/Desktop/books/three.lit
...
...&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I could have limited the Spotlight query further, but what fun would that be?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now, ultimately I&amp;#8217;m going to use this output with &lt;tt&gt;xargs&lt;/tt&gt;, but because of limitations imposed by the .lit conversion app, I need to get the basename of these files. For this &lt;tt&gt;sed&lt;/tt&gt; will do the trick:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre class='bash'&gt;mdfind -onlyin /Users/phil/Desktop/books/ &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;&amp;quot;kMDItemFSLabel&amp;nbsp;!= 6&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; | grep &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;&amp;quot;.lit&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; | \
    sed &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;'s/&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;Users&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;phil&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;Desktop&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;books&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;//'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre&gt;one.lit
two.lit
three.lit
...
...&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I pass this onto &lt;tt&gt;xargs&lt;/tt&gt;, then the unfortunately named &lt;a class='external text' href='http://www.convertlit.com' title='http://www.convertlit.com'&gt;ConvertLIT&lt;/a&gt; tool:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre class='bash'&gt;mdfind -onlyin /Users/phil/Desktop/books/ &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;&amp;quot;kMDItemFSLabel&amp;nbsp;!= 6&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; | grep &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;&amp;quot;.lit&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt; | \
    sed &lt;span style='color: #ff0000;'&gt;'s/&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;Users&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;phil&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;Desktop&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;books&lt;span style='color: #000099; font-weight: bold;'&gt;\/&lt;/span&gt;//'&lt;/span&gt;  | xargs -I \&lt;span style='color: #66cc66;'&gt;&amp;#123;&lt;/span&gt;\&lt;span style='color: #66cc66;'&gt;&amp;#125;&lt;/span&gt; clit \&lt;span style='color: #66cc66;'&gt;&amp;#123;&lt;/span&gt;\&lt;span style='color: #66cc66;'&gt;&amp;#125;&lt;/span&gt; oebps/\&lt;span style='color: #66cc66;'&gt;&amp;#123;&lt;/span&gt;\&lt;span style='color: #66cc66;'&gt;&amp;#125;&lt;/span&gt;/&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;pre&gt;$ clit one.lit oebps/one.lit/
$ clit two.lit oebps/two.lit/
$ clit three.lit oebps/three.lit/
$ ...
$ ...&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m replicating the syntax of &lt;tt&gt;find&lt;/tt&gt;&amp;#8217;s &lt;tt&gt;-exec&lt;/tt&gt; switch with &lt;tt&gt;xargs&lt;/tt&gt;&amp;#8217; &lt;tt&gt;-I&lt;/tt&gt; switch. This will replace all occurrences of the &lt;tt&gt;{}&lt;/tt&gt; with the filename from standard input.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/dw5pea==/ymfzaa==/2007/05/16/fun-with-xargs-on-mac-os-x</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/dw5pea==/ymfzaa==/2007/05/16/fun-with-xargs-on-mac-os-x</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-05-16T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Be a Composer In Three Easy Steps</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This is a paper I wrote at some point during my Master's work. I think I had to do it because I kept forgetting to go to class, but I don't remember putting this much effort into it. It does a decent job of describing how it felt to finally break through various mental blocks about songwriting and composition.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p style='text-align: right; font: 10.0px'&gt;[most emphasis is non-essential]&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;i&gt;compositional process&lt;/i&gt; has always been a difficult subject for me to adequately understand. For a long time I put forth a lot of effort to make my style of writing fit into a particular mold, only to be disappointed with the results. For an equally long time I had an idea of the kind of music I wanted to write, but I couldn't find the right method or approach to create this sound I heard.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This diatribe is a way for me to document the various discoveries I made as I began to develop my writing. Some of these things are really &quot;well, duh...&quot; kind of discoveries, but for me they are a way of simplifying &lt;b&gt;important concepts&lt;/b&gt; that I find &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;easy to forget&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although I've written music, in a way, as long as I've played any instrument, it has always been under the guise of improvisational jamming. In this sense, I was writing a piece every time I played any given song; perhaps this is why it was a long time before I ever really wrote a &lt;i&gt;completely original&lt;/i&gt; piece of music. As far as I was concerned, the songs were just platforms for (preferably) &lt;i&gt;group improvisation&lt;/i&gt;. Even after I began writing, &lt;b&gt;and to a certain extent even now,&lt;/b&gt; I always wrote with the intention of leaving space for improvisation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I soon realized how difficult this can be. Writing in such a manner is kind of &lt;i&gt;risky&lt;/i&gt;—not that I'm &lt;b&gt;risk-averse&lt;/b&gt;, but you have to accept that when you're taking a risk musically, in real time, sometimes it's just not going to work. &lt;b&gt;Sometimes, you're going to play shit&lt;/b&gt;, and there's nothing you can really do about it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, I knew there was other approaches that I wanted to explore. I have long had an interest in electronic music, but had never really considered creating it. This changed when I discovered &lt;b&gt;Apple Soundtrack&lt;/b&gt;, and more &lt;i&gt;specifically&lt;/i&gt;, the extensive loop library that came with it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As an aside, I have to acknowledge the role that &lt;b&gt;software piracy&lt;/b&gt; played in my development. Due to my history of &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;computational dorkery&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, I had access to a wealth of audio applications that I certainly could not have afforded at the time. As my professional experience grows, I'm slowly replacing oft-used software with legitimate copies, but I never could have scratched the surface of what's possible electronically without the access I had to this software.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;At any rate, working with loops in &lt;b&gt;Apple Soundtrack&lt;/b&gt; let me explore a variety of musical contexts without spending a lot of time building the fundamental components. I learned early on to disregard the pitch of the loops I was choosing, which led me to realize &lt;i&gt;Phil's Compositional Discovery #1&lt;/i&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;It's Good to Forget Everything You've Learned&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had been &lt;i&gt;struggling&lt;/i&gt; with repetition for some time. Even now it's easy for me to really get into a particular groove (or rut) with particular &lt;b&gt;concepts/sounds/patterns&lt;/b&gt;. For a long time I would try to use the various &lt;i&gt;theoretical&lt;/i&gt; tools at my disposal to try to &lt;i&gt;invent&lt;/i&gt; a chord progression, or melody. This would sometimes work, but the result didn't seem very &lt;i&gt;interesting&lt;/i&gt;. Every now and then, although I didn't realize it at the time, I would have success in&lt;b&gt;letting my ears find the chords&lt;/b&gt;, and the result was satisfying.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Working in prefabricated loops let me practice my arranging skills, and explore things that would take too long to try before. I also had the opportunity to really hear how it would sound if I juxtaposed some &lt;b&gt;rootsy funk&lt;/b&gt; against an &lt;b&gt;electro beat&lt;/b&gt;, or played &lt;i&gt;soothing piano melodies&lt;/i&gt; over &lt;i&gt;abstract atmospheres&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I soon outgrew &lt;b&gt;Soundtrack&lt;/b&gt;, and moved onto &lt;b&gt;Ableton Live&lt;/b&gt;, and then my personal favorite, &lt;b&gt;Reason&lt;/b&gt;. This software really allowed me to perform &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Rapid Composition Development&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, but this in itself started to concern me. It seemed so easy to grab assorted material and mash it all together, I felt there had to be a catch. I didn't believe I could really call what I was doing composition.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, months later, I had had the pleasure of composing some &lt;b&gt;really bad music&lt;/b&gt;, and it became clear that &lt;b&gt;there was some skill involved&lt;/b&gt;. I still attempt to avoid using any particular sample or preset in it's &lt;i&gt;unaltered&lt;/i&gt; form, but this did help me understand a phrase I read in Frank Zappa's autobiography:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;If It Sounds Good To You, Then It's Bitchen&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another facet of songwriting I have recently been practicing is &lt;i&gt;the complex art of lyric-writing&lt;/i&gt;. I'm not a stranger to the written word, but &lt;b&gt;I have a complex relationship with poetry&lt;/b&gt;, which seemed to me to be an analog to the lyrics I was trying to write. These complexities are basically due to the fact that most of the poetry I've written in my lifetime has been utterly secret, or shamefully &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;angsty&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This seemed to be reflected in my lyrics, at least in the fact that every song I've ever written with lyrics, at least until recently, were always about the women (or girls, at the time) that were causing me such &lt;b&gt;turmoil&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn't want to write the kind of &lt;i&gt;self-indulgent tripe&lt;/i&gt; that I heard on the Top 40 stations. These tunes weren't &lt;i&gt;terrible&lt;/i&gt;, but I still felt there was something that I didn't like about them. More recently, I thought some more on this matter, and decided that the primary thing that bothers me is &lt;b&gt;overuse of the first person&lt;/b&gt;. This is the foundation of another pseudo-discovery:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2&gt;&quot;I&quot; is a Dangerously Powerful Lyrical Tool&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The writer's &quot;I&quot; is something that needs to be used very &lt;i&gt;delicately&lt;/i&gt;, especially as a songwriter. Lyrics seem to have a powerful pressure on us as listeners, and the first person really has the ability to put the listener in a &lt;b&gt;serious place&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This idea has an associated concept, and that's the idea of literal word choice in songs. I would find myself struggling to express in song a particular situation that had happened, and I was being far too literal about everything. &lt;b&gt;&quot;Well, I can't use the word 'boardwalk' because it didn't happen there!&quot;&lt;/b&gt; The &lt;i&gt;realization&lt;/i&gt; that I could choose words that weren't literally significant while still retaining the initial thought was&lt;b&gt; just one more simple idea I had overlooked.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These ideas have recently all come together for me in a more tangible way, as I've begun developing a style of writing that I'm quite fond of. I've been trying for some time to combine my &lt;b&gt;groove-oriented&lt;/b&gt; interests with the &lt;b&gt;electronic world&lt;/b&gt; that I've been experimenting in. I am definitely a fan of &lt;b&gt;bizarre electronic noise pieces&lt;/b&gt;, but I have always felt a desire to write things that a person &lt;i&gt;less familiar with that style&lt;/i&gt; might understand.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The beginnings of this combination came to light while I was working on what was meant to be a reggae/ska version of &lt;i&gt;Dizzy Gillespie's&lt;/i&gt; &lt;b&gt;Night In Tunisia&lt;/b&gt;. This track, which I unfortunately could not resist calling &lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/home/jams/i-and-i-in-tunisia'&gt;I-and-I In Tunisia&lt;/a&gt;, was intended to be a sort of &lt;b&gt;dub piece&lt;/b&gt;, but I was experiencing problems in establishing the drum track. Without a real drummer at my disposal, I had resorted to my old standby of assorted drum loops culled from a variety of royalty-free collections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my attempts to rectify the situation, I began experimenting with &lt;b&gt;Reason&lt;/b&gt; through &lt;b&gt;ReWire&lt;/b&gt;. I tried some various &lt;i&gt;electronic beats&lt;/i&gt;, and as my exploration deepened, I started seeing how &lt;b&gt;far out&lt;/b&gt; I could get and still finish the tune normally—I was hoping to maintain the jazz 'head tune' format, and still end with a couple of choruses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although I never really acknowledge a piece as being &lt;i&gt;finished&lt;/i&gt;, I was pretty happy with the results of &lt;b&gt;I-and-I In Tunisia&lt;/b&gt;. I continued to explore these concepts in a subsequent piece, &lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/music/interlude.mp3'&gt;interlude&lt;/a&gt;, which also features a &lt;i&gt;preliminary&lt;/i&gt; set of lyrics.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was one of the first songs with lyrics that I've written in some time, but during the writing process I noticed myself using some lyrical tools I'd gleaned from the &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;hip-hop&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; acts I've been getting into lately. Although I certainly don't pretend to have the wordplay skills of the &lt;b&gt;Digable Planets&lt;/b&gt;, or &lt;b&gt;A Tribe Called Quest&lt;/b&gt;, I definitely attempted to employ simpler constructs like &lt;i&gt;alliteration&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;assonance&lt;/i&gt;, as well as inner and partial rhymes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I may not have succeeded completely at this task, but it was an important development that I was &lt;i&gt;consciously&lt;/i&gt; thinking about these things while I was writing. I remember once telling someone that as far as I was concerned, &lt;b&gt;lyrics happened by magic&lt;/b&gt;. I didn't have any real understanding of them, I just wrote them down as I thought up ways to finish a rhyme, and I was &lt;i&gt;glad to get anything&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, &lt;b&gt;interlude&lt;/b&gt; features one of the more successful &lt;i&gt;electronic breakdowns&lt;/i&gt; that I have attempted in a piece, as it transitions into the outro guitar solo. Unlike in &lt;b&gt;I-and-I In Tunisia&lt;/b&gt;, I disregard the original groove completely, except for a couple of bars of drums lead-into the &lt;b&gt;original groove&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I'm less than thrilled with the current version of the guitar work in this piece, but I try not to get too hung up with that &lt;i&gt;particular element&lt;/i&gt;. I find it difficult to produce quality improvised guitar lines without a live band. This in itself may be a hang-up, but my intent is for this piece to grow with a live band (&lt;b&gt;which will be happening soon&lt;/b&gt;), so that element is not too &lt;i&gt;high&lt;/i&gt; on my priority list yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was also the first piece I've completed (or nearly completed, as the case may be) on my new &lt;b&gt;Mac G5&lt;/b&gt;, which has already freed me of a lot of confines on its own. Like &lt;b&gt;Soundtrack&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Reason&lt;/b&gt;, a good recording rig allows a &lt;i&gt;composer&lt;/i&gt; to &lt;i&gt;explore&lt;/i&gt; so much &lt;i&gt;more&lt;/i&gt;, and the results even thus far have been well worth the cost. However, I have to say the process of learning various audio tools on a &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;lesser system&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; instilled in me a certain level of &lt;b&gt;efficiency&lt;/b&gt; that will allow me to put my rig to its best use.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The personal progress I've made over the last few years is really &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;profound&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; for me to look back on. Particularly when I first arrived at graduate school, I spent a huge amount of time &lt;b&gt;justifying my existence as a writer&lt;/b&gt;. Since my application process was so long, taking essentially three tries to be accepted to the program, by the time I finally got in I had developed a real &lt;i&gt;self-flaggelation complex&lt;/i&gt;. I really felt a need to prove to myself that I really could call myself a composer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This was certainly daunting &lt;i&gt;emotionally&lt;/i&gt;, but it developed into a real work ethic that I hadn't experienced before. The individual discoveries were made more significant because I had spent so much time trying to find them. I had wanted to be able to write music for a long time, and by the time I realized I could,&lt;b&gt; I'd been already been writing for years&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think the best way for me to end this rambling piece of personal pseudo-analysis is with another quote from one of my greatest influences, &lt;b&gt;Frank Zappa&lt;/b&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote style='font: 18.0px Cochin'&gt;The most important thing in art is &lt;b&gt;The Frame&lt;/b&gt;. For painting, literally; for other arts, figuratively—because, without this humble appliance, you can't &lt;b&gt;know&lt;/b&gt; where &lt;i&gt;The Art&lt;/i&gt; stops and &lt;i&gt;The Real World&lt;/i&gt; begins.

You have to put a 'box' around it because otherwise, &lt;b&gt;what is that shit on the wall?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2007/05/08/be-a-composer-in-three-easy-steps</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2007/05/08/be-a-composer-in-three-easy-steps</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-05-08T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Notes on Mod_Python and Apache 2.2 on Mac OS X</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m hoping to get away from PHP in favor of mod_python, but the first thing I needed to do was get mod_python successfully working on Mac OS X. I tried once before, using the built-in Apache and Python binaries that ship with Mac OS X. At the time (I think this was still 10.4, but it could have been 10.3), the built-in Python wasn’t multithreaded (or something like that) and the mod_python developers were starting to move away from Apache 1.3 altogether.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had success recently compiling mod_python on Mac OS X Server, against the distributed (but inactive) Apache 2 installation in /opt. However, I found OS X Server to be basically garbage, so I did a fresh install of the client version of Mac OS X, and set about getting Apache 2 to compile, and then mod_python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was not easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;xcode_24_tools&quot;&gt;XCode 2.4 Tools&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apache 2 compiles fine with older versions, but mod_python has problems. Make sure to install the latest version of the XCode tools, available at &lt;a href='http://developer.apple.com'&gt;Apple’s Developer Site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;python_244_pythonmacorg_distribution&quot;&gt;Python 2.4.4 (pythonmac.org distribution)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You should be able to use any thread-enabled version of Python, but I choose to use Bob Ippolito’s python distribution from (pythonmac.org)[http://pythonmac.org/packages/py24-fat/index.html]. Also, I did choose 2.4.4 instead of 2.5, but I would imagine 2.5 would work just as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;expat_20&quot;&gt;Expat 2.0&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It looks like Mac OS X 10.4.9 at least doesn’t come with a up-to-date version of libexpat, so we install one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure --mandir=/usr/local/share/man CFLAGS=-O2&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;apache_224&quot;&gt;Apache 2.2.4&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First cd into srclib/apr and do the usual configure-make (but not install) routine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then cd into srclib/apr-util and configure it to use our precompiled apr and the new installed version of libexpat:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure --with-apr=../apr --with-expat=/usr/local&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;followed by a make (but again, no install).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, in the main Apache2 build directory, run this configure line to somewhat mimic the Debian style:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;CFLAGS=&amp;quot;-arch ppc -isysroot /Developer/SDKs/MacOSX10.4u.sdk&amp;quot; \
./configure --prefix=/etc/apache2 --exec-prefix=/usr/local --datadir=/usr/local/share \
--sysconfdir=/etc/apache2 --sharedstatedir=/usr/local/common --localstatedir=/usr/local/var \
--includedir=/usr/local/include --infodir=/usr/local/info --mandir=/usr/local/man --enable-so \
--enable-mods-shared=all --with-mpm=prefork --with-apr=srclib/apr --with-apr-util=srclib/apr-util&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tweaks_and_configuration_changes&quot;&gt;Tweaks and Configuration Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all, I had to turn off a number of extra modules I don’t ever use. I like having them around, which is why I built them all, but I also discovered I don’t know quite as much about which-modules-do-what as I thought I did. A little investigation later and things were good, except for the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Had to make sure the TypesConfig directive was pointing to the right place, with: &lt;code&gt;TypesConfig /private/etc/httpd/mime.types&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For now, Apache doesn’t seem to know where to look for the config file. It tries to find it at &lt;code&gt;/httpd.conf&lt;/code&gt;, so for now I have to launch the apache process manually, and can’t use &lt;tt&gt;apachectl&lt;/tt&gt;. This is probably a problem with my configure line, but I can’t figure out what, since I definitely included &lt;code&gt;--sysconfdir&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;For some reason, after all this I had a problem with my Subversion installation. Normally, I use the subversion package found at (Metissian)[http://metissian.com/projects/macosx/subversion/], but this seemed damaged or otherwise broken because I was getting an error similar to the one I was getting from the mod_python configure process (before I recompiled expat).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;retarded_hacks_to_fix_above&quot;&gt;Retarded Hacks to Fix above&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after config, in &lt;tt&gt;include/ap_config_auto.h&lt;/tt&gt; Change AP_TYPES_CONFIG_FILE to /private/etc/httpd/mime.types Change SERVER_CONFIG_FILE to /etc/apache2/httpd.conf&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;mod_python_331&quot;&gt;mod_python 3.3.1&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;./configure --with-apxs2=/usr/local/bin/apxs --with-python=/usr/local/bin/python2.4&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/yxbhy2hl/dw5pea==/y29tcglsaw5n/2007/05/01/notes-on-mod_python-and-apache-2-2-on-mac-os-x</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/yxbhy2hl/dw5pea==/y29tcglsaw5n/2007/05/01/notes-on-mod_python-and-apache-2-2-on-mac-os-x</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Concerts I Have Seen</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;The criteria I’ll use to dictate whether or not to list something would involve how much of an impact the show made on me. In the case of opening acts, if I remember their name and music, I’ll list them. I couldn’t possibly cover all the smaller shows I’ve seen, so I’m not even going to count shows by my peers and so forth. &lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Phish &lt;a href='http://www.ihoz.com/cgi/statsfromfile?url=http://bubblehouse.org/phishshows.html'&gt;&lt;small&gt;(stats)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Camp Oswego – Oswego, NY – 1999/07/17-18 Blue Cross Arena – Rochester, NY – 1999/12/05 Big Cypress Indian Reservation – Big Cypress, FL – 1999/12/30-2000/01/01 Pepsi Arena – Albany, NY – 2000/09/08-09 Darien Lake Amphitheater – Darien Center, NY – 2000/09/14 Hershey Stadium – Hershey, PA – 2000/09/15 Hampton Coliseum – Hampton, VA – 2003/01/02-04 Uniondale, NY – 2003/02/28 Burgettstown, PA – 2003/07/29 IT – Limestone, ME – 2003/08/02-03 Pepsi Arena – Albany, NY – 2003/12/01 Keystone Park – Brooklyn, NY – 2003/06/18 SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 2003/06/20 Hampton Coliseum – Hampton, VA – 2009/03/06-08 Fenway Park – Boston, MA – 2009/05/31 Jones Beach amphitheater – Jones Beach, NY – 2009/06/2 Darien Lake – Darien Center, NY – 2009/08/13 SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 2009/08/16 Empire Polo Grounds – Indio, NY – 2009/10/30-11/01&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Medeski, Martin and Wood&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Geneva Opera House – Geneva, NY – 2000/12/02 Lost Horizon – Syracuse, NY – 2001/10/26 RPI Fieldhouse – Troy, NY – 2001/10/27 The Egg – Albany, NY – 2005/02/25 The Egg – Albany, NY – 2006/04/05 Hammerstein Ballroom – Albany, NY – 2006/10/31 Tarrytown Music Hall – Tarrytown, NY – 2007/04/26 Rothbury Festival – Rochbury, MI – 2008/07/05 Camp MMW – Big Indian, NY – 2008/08/05-2008/08/10 92YTribeca – New York, NY – 2008/02/17 Le Poisson Rouge – New York, NY – 2008/02/18 City Winery – New York, NY – 2008/02/19 Nokia Theater – New York, NY $ndash; 2008/11/14&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Trey Anastasio&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landmark Theater – Syracuse, NY – 2001/02/22 SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 2001/08/05 Darien Lake Amphitheater – Darien Center, NY – 2002/06/16 Palace Theater – Albany, NY – 2002/06/13 Burlington Performing Arts Center – Burlington, VT – 2003/06/07-08 Utica Coliseum – Utica, NY – 2005/11/11 State Theater – Albany, NY – 2005/11/18 Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/06 Palace Theater – Albany, NY – 2008/10/18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;moe.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Landmark Theater – Syracuse, NY – 2001/03/02 Laker Hall – Oswego, NY – 2001/04/29 Landmark Theater – Syracuse, NY – 2002/04/18&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;String Cheese Incident&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RPI Fieldhouse – Troy, NY – 2001/10/27 Landmark Theater – Syracuse, NY – 2001/10/28&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Lotus&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bowery Ballroom – New York, NY – 2007/11/03 Fillmore East at Irving Plaza – New York, NY – 2008 Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/03 Mercury Lounge – New York, NY – 2009/09/19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perpetual Groove – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/03 Zappa Plays Zappa – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/03 Disco Biscuits – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/03&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snoop Dogg – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/04 311 – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/04 Modest Mouse – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/04 Sage Francis – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/04&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Franti and Spearhead – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/05 Derek Trucks and Susan Tedeschi – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/05 Dave Matthews Band – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/05&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mike Gordon – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/06 Phil Lesh and Friends – Rothbury Festival – Rothbury, MI – 2008/07/06&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phil Lesh and Friends – Nokia Theater – New York, NY – 2008/11/08&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New Deal – Bowery Ballroom – New York, NY – 2008&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Join – Revolution Hall – Troy, NY – 2007/12/28 The Join – Highline Ballroom – New York, NY – 2007/12/31&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Breakfast – Sullivan Hall – New York, NY – 2007&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jacob Fred Jazz Odyssey – Sullivan Hall – New York, NY – 2008/06/20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tarantula – The Egg – Albany, NY – 2005/02/25 Vida Blue – State Theater – Ithaca, NY – 2002/04/21 The Other Ones – Civic Center – Syracuse, NY – 2000/09/12 Ziggy Marley – Civic Center – Syracuse, NY – 2000/09/12 John Medeski and Bob Moses – The Stone – New York, NY – 2006/09/19 Manbreak – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY Live – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY Counting Crows – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 1997/07/27 The Wallflowers – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 1997/07/27 HORDE Festival – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 1996 Dave Matthews and Tim Reynolds – Stanley Theater – Utica, NY – 1996 HORDE Festival – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 1997/08/10 Smashing Pumpkins – Knickerbocker Arena – Albany, NY – 1996 Garbage – Knickerbocker Arena – Albany, NY – 1996 B.B. King – Stanley Theater – Utica, NY – 2005/04/07 Ben Folds – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 1998/06/06 Beck – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 1998/06/06 The Dead – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 2006/07/02 GRAB – SPAC – Saratoga Springs, NY – 2006/07/02 Reel Big Fish – Hewitt Union – Oswego, NY Springheeled Jack USA – Hewitt Union – Oswego, NY They Might Be Giants – Hewitt Union – Oswego, NY – 1997/11/23 Lincoln – Hewitt Union – Oswego, NY – 1997/11/23 Benevento-Russo Duo – Tribeca Rock Club – New York, NY Mike Doughty – Randall’s Island – New York, NY Oysterhead – Utica Coliseum – Utica, NY – 2001/11/09 Lake Trout – Utica Coliseum – Utica, NY – 2001/11/09 Grassroots Festival – 1997 Charlie Hunter Trio – Waterman Theater – Oswego, NY Son Seals – Camp Oswego – Oswego, NY – 1999/07/17-18 The Slip – Camp Oswego – Oswego, NY – 1999/07/17-18 Ozomatli – Camp Oswego – Oswego, NY – 1999/07/17-18&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/2007/05/01/concerts-i-have-seen</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/2007/05/01/concerts-i-have-seen</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-05-01T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>star wars expanded universe books i have read</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;These are listed in cannonical chronological order. A full list is available &lt;a href='http://starwars.wikia.com/wiki/List_of_books'&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;&lt;style type='text/css'&gt;&lt;![CDATA[
.finished-booklist {
counter-reset: total;
}

.finished-book {
counter-increment: total 1; 
}
.finished-book:before {
content: counter(total) &quot;. &quot;;
}
]]&gt;&lt;/style&gt;&lt;div class='finished-booklist'&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Darth Bane: Path of Destruction (2006)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Darth Bane: Rule of Two (2008)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Saboteur (2001)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Cloak of Deception (2001)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Shadow Hunter (2001)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;(Episode I)&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Rogue Planet (2000)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Outbound Flight (2006)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Approaching Storm (2002)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;(Episode II)&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Clone Wars&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Republic Commando: Hard Contact (2004)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Shatterpoint (2003)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Cestus Deception (2004)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Hive (2004)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Republic Commando: Triple Zero (2006)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;MedStar I: Battle Surgeon (2004)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;MedStar II: Jedi Healer (2004)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Jedi Trial (2004)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Yoda: Dark Renezvous (2004)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Labyrinth of Evil (2005)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Republic Commando: Order 66 (2008)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;strong&gt;(Episode III)&lt;/strong&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Coruscant Nights I: Jedi Twilight (2008)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Coruscant Nights II: Street of Shadows (2008)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Dark Lord: The Rise of Darth Vader (2005)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Force Unleashed (2008)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Han Solo Trilogy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Paradise Snare (1997)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Hutt Gambit (1997)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Rebel Dawn (1998)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Han Solo Adventures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Han Solo at Star's End (1979)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Han Solo's Revenge (1979)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Han Solo and the Lost Legacy (1980)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Lando Calrissian Adventures&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Mindharp of Sharu (1983)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Flamewind of Oseon (1983)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The StarCave of ThonBoka (1983)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Death Star (2007)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Episode IV)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Splinter of the Mind's Eye (1978)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Allegiance (2007)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Episode V)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Luke Skywalker and the Shadows of Mindor (2008)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Shadows of the Empire (1996)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Episode VI)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Truce at Bakura (1993)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Courtship of Princess Leia (1994)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Tatooine Ghost (2003)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dark Forces&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Soldier for the Empire (1997)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Rebel Agent (1998)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Jedi Knight (1998)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Thrawn Trilogy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Heir to the Empire (1991)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Dark Force Rising (1992)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Last Command (1993)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Callista Ming Saga&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Children of the Jedi (1995)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Darksaber (1995)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Planet of Twilight (1997)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt; I, Jedi (1998)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Jedi Academy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Jedi Search (1994)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Dark Apprentice (1994)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Champions of the Force (1994)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Crystal Star (1994)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Black Fleet Crisis&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Before the Storm (1996)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Shield of Lies (1996)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Tyrant's Test (1996)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The New Rebellion (1996)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Corellian Trillogy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Ambush at Corellia (1995)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Assault on Selonia (1995)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Showdown at Centerpoint (1995)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The Hand of Thrawn Duology&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Specter of the Past (1997)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Vision of the Future (1998)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Survivor's Quest (2004)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;The New Jedi Order&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Vector Prime (1999)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Dark Tide I: Onslaught (2000)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Dark Tide II: Ruin (2000)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Agents of Chaos I: Hero's Trial (2000)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Agents of Chaos II: Jedi Eclipse (2000)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Balance Point (2000)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Recovery (2001)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Edge of Victory I: Conquest (2001)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Edge of Victory II: Rebirth (2001)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Emissary of the Void (2001)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Star by Star (2001)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Dark Journey (2002)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Traitor (2002)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Destiny's Way (2002)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Force Heretic I: Remnant (2003)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Force Heretic II: Refugee (2003)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Force Heretic III: Reunion (2003)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Final Prophecy (2003)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Unifying Force (2003)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Dark Nest Trilogy&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Joiner King (2005)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Unseen Queen (2005)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;The Swarm War (2005)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Legacy Of The Force&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Betrayal (2006)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Bloodlines (2006)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Tempest (2006)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Exile (2007)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Sacrifice (2007)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Inferno (2007)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Fury (2007)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Revelation (2008)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Invincible (2008)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Fate Of The Jedi&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Outcast (2009)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class='finished-book'&gt;Omen (2009)&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/2007/03/03/star-wars-expanded-universe-books-i-have-read</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/2007/03/03/star-wars-expanded-universe-books-i-have-read</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Pattern-Based Drilling</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Begin with this basic graphical pattern:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e---------
B------o--
G----o----
D--o------
A---------
E---------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Play the pattern repeatedly, increasing by one half-step each time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e---------------------------
B------5-----6-----7-----8--
G----4-----5-----6-----7----
D--3-----4-----5-----6------
A---------------------------
E---------------------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you are able to play it all over the fretboard, start concentrating on picking technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focus on using alternate picking for every note, so that the pattern of picking alternates for each group, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e-------- ------- ------- --------
B------5- -----6- -----7- -----8--
G----4--- ---5--- ---6--- ---7----
D--3----- -4----- -5----- -6------
A-------- ------- ------- --------
E-------- ------- ------- --------
   ^ v ^   v ^ v   ^ v ^   v ^ v&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next play that same pattern followed by the mirror image of the original pattern, like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e---------
B------o--
G----o---- &amp;lt;----------- flip
D--o------
A---------
E---------

e---------
B--o------
G----o---- &amp;lt;----------- flip
D------o--
A---------
E---------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If played from the third fret D string, the pattern would be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e---------------
B------5-3------
G----4-----4----
D--3---------5--
A---------------
E---------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This too should be played up and down the fretboard:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e---------------------------------------
B------5-3---------6-4---------7-5------
G----4-----4-----5-----5-----6-----6----
D--3---------5-4---------6-5---------7--
A---------------------------------------
E---------------------------------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, your picking technique will be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e---------------
B------5-3------
G----4-----4----
D--3---------5--
A---------------
E---------------
   ^ v ^ v ^ v&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can easily make other simple permutations to these patterns. Here’s what the result would be if you took the previous cell and played it in reverse, in a descending pattern.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e---------------------------------------
B------5-7---------4-6---------3-5------
G----6-----6-----5-----5-----4-----4----
D--7---------5-6---------4-5---------3--
A---------------------------------------
E---------------------------------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These patterns can be used in improvisation pretty easily too, particularly as a device for building tension before a release. For example, there’s an altered form of this pattern in the minor pentatonic scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example in A minor:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e--------------------------
B------*10*-----11-----12--
G----*9*----*10*----11-----
D-*7*------8-----*9*-------
A--------------------------
E--------------------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The marked notes are the tonic and dominant notes in the A minor pentatonic scale, but the last two notes are the 3rd and 9th in the A dorian, which is a nice flavor switch when soloing in a pentatonic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, that last B is only a passing tone in the dorian mode, so to resolve it (the “release” after the suspense of the passing tones), just raise it up to the thirteenth fret.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here it is with a walk across the tonic and down the dorian scale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;e----------------------------------------------------
B-------10------11-----12-12/13-12-10----10----------
G-----9------10-----11----------------12----12-10-9--
D--7-------8------9----------------------------------
A----------------------------------------------------
E----------------------------------------------------&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When practicing technique-oriented material, it can be helpful to drop your theoretical guard and focus on the visual aspects of playing. This comes naturally to many guitarists, but it’s easy to get distracted or bored with the repetition of drilling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding arbitrary permutations of sample patterns is a good way to feel constructive in your practicing, as many of these patterns can find their way into your regular improvisation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/z3vpdgfy/bgvzc29ucw==/2007/02/19/pattern-based-drilling</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/z3vpdgfy/bgvzc29ucw==/2007/02/19/pattern-based-drilling</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-02-19T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>japh</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style='font-family:courier;font-size:9;'&gt;#!/usr/bin/perl @x=(0x50,-82,0xd,-3,-12,0x5,0x1,0xd,0x41,-84,0x1, -2,0x2b,0x4a);$Z=sub{for($z=@_;$z;$z–){unshift( @z,chr($_[$z]+$z{z}));$z{z}+=$_[$z];}while($z=pop (@z)){print($z);}};$z=$Z;@Z=(0xd,-6,0x8,0x2);$Z-&amp;gt; ((0,0,0,-68,@Z,-7,0x48,-76,-6,0xd,-11,@x));&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/cgvyba==/cmvmbgv4aw9ucw==/2007/02/17/japh</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/cgvyba==/cmvmbgv4aw9ucw==/2007/02/17/japh</guid>
                <pubDate>2007-02-17T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>pedals and pedals and pedals</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://bubblehouse.org/home/?q=system/files/12-08-06_0037.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Top Row:&lt;/h3&gt;
Ernie Ball VP Jr., Voodoo Labs Pedal Power 2+, Dunlop Crybaby, Sovtek Big Muff Pi, Boss Metal Zone
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Bottom Row:&lt;/h3&gt;
Boss Loopstation XL-20, Boss Digital Delay DD-3, Analogman King of Tone, Analogman Bi-Comprossor, Boss Octave OC-3
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/z3vpdgfy/2006/12/08/pedals-and-pedals-and-pedals</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/z3vpdgfy/2006/12/08/pedals-and-pedals-and-pedals</guid>
                <pubDate>2006-12-08T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>my fridge</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;this is truly the saddest thing i’ve ever seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!--break--&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://bubblehouse.org/home/?q=system/files/12-07-06_0032.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src='http://bubblehouse.org/home/?q=system/files/12-07-06_0033.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/c2fk/2006/12/07/my-fridge</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/c2fk/2006/12/07/my-fridge</guid>
                <pubDate>2006-12-07T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>New York Theatre Review: InsideOut</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;We got a pretty favorable review on &lt;a href='http://www.nytheatre.com/nytheatre/archweb/arch2006_10.htm#236'&gt;NewYorkTheatre.com&lt;/a&gt;. They were kind of harsh with regards to the script, but gave a favorable review overall. And of course, my favorite part:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;...The result is a paranoid and claustrophobic mood that manages to be hypnotically appealing at the same time. In this regard, InsideOut is indebted to its design elements, &lt;b&gt;particularly sound and music designer Phil Christensen's eerily seductive techno score.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;(emphasis mine)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I couldn't help but giggle a little bit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/cmv2awv3cw==/2006/12/06/new-york-theatre-review-insideout</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/cmv2awv3cw==/2006/12/06/new-york-theatre-review-insideout</guid>
                <pubDate>2006-12-06T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>the light in my room was too bright</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;so i made a lampshade for it… &lt;!--break--&gt; &lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/home/system/files/sconce.jpg'&gt;&lt;img alt='lampshade' border='0' src='http://bubblehouse.org/home/system/files/sconce.jpg' /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2006/08/25/the-light-in-my-room-was-too-bright</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2006/08/25/the-light-in-my-room-was-too-bright</guid>
                <pubDate>2006-08-25T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>beginning of day timestamps</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.driveling.net/'&gt;mark&lt;/a&gt; got me thinking about this, and then i was messing around with one of my own projects that needed the same feature, and i realized the easy way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;i would always get the year/month/day out of a timestamp using the date() function, and then create a new timestamp with mktime().&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;i just realized the best way is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;$now = time(); $beginning&lt;em&gt;of&lt;/em&gt;day = $now - ($now % 86400);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this works for me because i definitely remember that number for seconds in a day, and avoids any locale-dependent variations. plus, end of day becomes just as easy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/cghw/cmvmbgv4aw9ucw==/2006/08/01/beginning-of-day-timestamps</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/cghw/cmvmbgv4aw9ucw==/2006/08/01/beginning-of-day-timestamps</guid>
                <pubDate>2006-08-01T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>yipyipyipyipyipyipyipyip uh-huh uh-huh</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MKX0RN19zc0 '&gt;phone home&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g5X7ztdd_6E&amp;amp;NR'&gt;old macdonald had a spaceship&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uriYIMa35Hg'&gt;meet the computer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/zxnvdgvyawnh/2006/07/27/yipyipyipyipyipyipyipyip-uh-huh-uh-huh</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/zxnvdgvyawnh/2006/07/27/yipyipyipyipyipyipyipyip-uh-huh-uh-huh</guid>
                <pubDate>2006-07-27T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>working with the diminished scale</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working with the dimished scale lately, and I thought it might be a good idea to document how I wrap my mind around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First off, let’s start with a diagram of a diminished scale:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='diminished scale' class='transparent' src='/home/?q=system/files/diminished-scale.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The black dots represent the chord itself, while the grey dots are alternate locations to play notes of the chord. As far as fret numberings go, if you wished to play the Bb diminished scale, you would start by placing that first note at Bb, or the sixth fret. However, due to the “overlapping” nature of the diminished scale, you would also simultaneously be playing in the D, F, and Ab diminished scales.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you start with the first black dot on the &lt;strong&gt;low E&lt;/strong&gt; string, and follow the black dots left to right on each string in sequence, you’ll end up playing through the octave twice, with one note left over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next thing to grasp is how this pattern repeats itself on the fretboard. I like to think of connection points between fretboard patterns, and this scale provides some easy ones. This next diagram illustrates where this pattern repeats; the pattern starting from the first pair of highlighted notes is repeated after the second pair of notes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='diminished scale connections' class='transparent' src='/home/?q=system/files/diminished-connections.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you understand that, the entire pattern simplifies to this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='simplified diminished scale' class='transparent' src='/home/?q=system/files/diminished-simplified.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, if you ever get lost (say, mid-jam), the easiest thing is to do is remember that on any given string, the diminished notes always have two frets between them. Eventually the patterns will start to make sense again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point I should mention a semantic issue. I tend to refer to the previous scale as the ‘diminished scale’, but that terminology is often used to describe a scale consisting of alternating whole and half steps. This is also often referred to as the &lt;strong&gt;octatonic scale&lt;/strong&gt; which looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt='octatonic scale' class='transparent' src='/home/?q=system/files/octatonic-scale.png' /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this isn’t as complicated as it looks. You’re simply adding a note a half step below every note you were playing before (indicated by the circles). It’s called a diminished scale because it does, in fact, contain the entire diminished chord for the given key.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;References:&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href='http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diminished_scale'&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diminished_scale&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/z3vpdgfy/bgvzc29ucw==/2006/07/18/working-with-the-diminished-scale</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/z3vpdgfy/bgvzc29ucw==/2006/07/18/working-with-the-diminished-scale</guid>
                <pubDate>2006-07-18T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>warts and all</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of April, I got some friends and cohorts together to record a live ep, consisting of some of my &amp;#8220;classics&amp;#8221;. following a delusional miles davis complex, i decided not to give the players anything to listen to of the tracks we were about to record, so they only had one rehearsal before the big day.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;i specifically wanted something filled with &amp;#8220;the human element&amp;#8221;, and i got exactly that. this was kind of my response to the sterilized studio environment at suny purchase, and i was very happy with the results&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pcb/ep/01_ghetto_queen.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;ghetto queen&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pcb/ep/02_pathways.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;pathways&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pcb/ep/03_who_stepped_on_dizs_horn.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;who stepped on diz&amp;#8217;s horn&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen/Wilson)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pcb/ep/04_harvest.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;harvest&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen/Hovish)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pcb/ep/05_if_i_could_see.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;if i could see&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;The players on this session were:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;Matt Wilson&lt;/b&gt;, bass, co-author &lt;i&gt;who stepped on diz&amp;#8217;s horn&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;Josh Ballard&lt;/b&gt;, piano/organ&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;Rory Merola&lt;/b&gt;, drums&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;b&gt;Mike Spivack&lt;/b&gt;, engineering, production assistance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/05/23/warts-and-all</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/05/23/warts-and-all</guid>
                <pubDate>2005-05-23T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>diary of a madman</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='/cgi-bin/download.cgi/diary_of_a_madman.mp3'&gt;diary of a madman&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/03/03/diary-of-a-madman</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/03/03/diary-of-a-madman</guid>
                <pubDate>2005-03-03T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>higher than you</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='/cgi-bin/download.cgi/higher_than_you.mp3'&gt;higher than you&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;&lt;i&gt;(christensen)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/02/20/higher-than-you</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/02/20/higher-than-you</guid>
                <pubDate>2005-02-20T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>the only sure things in life are death and spammers</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;just when i was sure i was out, they pulled me back in!!!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;lately my exposure to spam has been relatively low. since i got spamassassin working to it&amp;#8217;s fullest by utilizing the &lt;a href='http://razor.sourceforge.net/'&gt;razor db&lt;/a&gt;, the amount of false negatives i&amp;#8217;ve gotten is damn close to zero. i can&amp;#8217;t remember the last time a spam e-mail got through to my inbox.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;also, awhile ago i realized that &lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/archives/000057.shtml'&gt;spammers were the only ones submitting comments on my blog&lt;/a&gt;, which led me to start using &lt;a href='http://james.seng.sg'&gt;James Seng&amp;#8217;s&lt;/a&gt; SCode.pm for generating CAPTCHAs, which stopped the problem for the most part. I was still getting spammed manually, though.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;however, today i became aware of two other ways those smarmy bastards were getting through. first, i realized that my referrer logs were full to the brim with URLs like http://texas-hold-em.online-deals-4u.info/&amp;#8230;. a &lt;a href='http://it.slashdot.org/article.pl?sid=05/02/01/1519211&amp;amp;tid=111&amp;amp;tid=95&amp;amp;tid=4'&gt;slashdot article&lt;/a&gt; proved informative in fixing this issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;and finally, i realized that the once pristine TrackBack mechanism was also getting spammed, leading me to turn off that feature throughout my site. apparently, though, Mr. Seng also has &lt;a href='http://james.seng.sg/archives/2005/02/04/solution_to_trackback_spams.html'&gt;a solution to this&lt;/a&gt;, which i hope to implement soon&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;as a sidenote, while preparing this entry, i came upon some information about &lt;a href='http://www.drupal.org/'&gt;Drupal&lt;/a&gt;, an open-source content management platform. it looks kinda nice, and i&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about freeing myself from Six Apart&amp;#8217;s moveabletype software&amp;#8230;it will be interesting to see what&amp;#8217;s involved in making the switch&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;EDIT: for the moment, i&amp;#8217;ve started using tom sherman&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href='http://underscorebleach.net/content/jotsheet/2005/02/prevent_movable_type_trackback_spam'&gt;solution to trackback spam&lt;/a&gt;, and it seems to be doing the job&amp;#8230;.i&amp;#8217;m still looking at drupal, though&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2005/02/04/the-only-sure-things-in-life-are-death-and-spammers</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2005/02/04/the-only-sure-things-in-life-are-death-and-spammers</guid>
                <pubDate>2005-02-04T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>new stuff, and junk</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;here&amp;#8217;s a couple of tunes in the usual semi-finished demo state&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/lost.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;lost&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/miss_direction.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;miss direction&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;&lt;p&gt;and here&amp;#8217;s a bunch of junk&amp;#8230;including the rough cut of a reggae version of Slayer&amp;#8217;s &amp;#8220;Raining Blood&amp;#8221; that we&amp;#8217;re working on in one of my studio practicum classes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/raining_dub_rough_track.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;raining dub&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/zuperphunk.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;zuperphunk&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/walking_groove.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;walking groove&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/smell_the_capital.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;smell the capital&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pfunk_garbage.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;pfunk garbage&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/desert_groove.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;desert groove&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/crazy_bitch.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;crazy bitch&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/i_wear_my_shame_like_a_wet_towel.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;i wear my shame like a wet towel&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/funkeee.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;funkeee&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/02/01/new-stuff-and-junk</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2005/02/01/new-stuff-and-junk</guid>
                <pubDate>2005-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>A Message To The Red States</title>
                <description>&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;layout: post
title: a message to the red states
created: 1099676343
categories:
- !ruby/string:Sequel::SQL::Blob |-
  cmFudHM=
- !ruby/string:Sequel::SQL::Blob |-&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h2 id='_zxhjzxjwdhm'&gt;  ZXhjZXJwdHM=&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;A HREF='http://www.theregister.co.uk/2004/11/07/blue_state_to_reds/'&gt;http://www.theregister.co.uk/2004/11/07/blue&lt;em&gt;state&lt;/em&gt;to_reds/&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;H2&gt;Reach out and sneer: Dem radicals speak to the Red States&lt;/H2&gt;&lt;H3&gt;By New Democrat Outreach Program&lt;/H3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Published Sunday 7th November 2004 12:30&amp;#160;GMT&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The defeated Kerry may have called for unity last week, but already radical elements inside and outside of the Democrat party are arguing for the abandonment of the old ways of cosy consensus. One such organisation, formed even as the last queues for the ballots ebbed away, styles itself &amp;#8220;The New Democrat Outreach Program.&amp;#8221; The Register has been contacted by one NDOP activist, styling himself Commandante Camembert, with an early draft of the organisation&amp;#8217;s first communique to the nation. &amp;#8220;We must,&amp;#8221; says Camembert, &amp;#8220;learn to speak to all of the people. But we mustn&amp;#8217;t be afraid to sneer when we do it.&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We think they&amp;#8217;ve got that right already, although the &amp;#8220;outreach&amp;#8221; may need some work. Anway, here it is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;H1&gt;An open letter to the Red-State victors:&lt;/H1&gt;&lt;p&gt;With hard work and superb organization, you have triumphed over John Kerry and the forces of Blue-state paternalism. Congratulations. The multinational corporations that hold you in bondage remain free to profit off your sweat nearly tax free, while their overpaid senior execs continue to pay a pittance in personal income tax.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your primary and secondary schools will continue to turn out third-rate pupils with limited opportunities, while you enjoy the satisfaction of making it on your own without health care when a catastrophic illness bankrupts your family.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your agricultural universities will continue issuing Ph.D.s in football, and bogus Protestant Evangelical and Fundamentalist theology, and how to jerk off a bull safely. Your children will learn to borrow enough money to erect chicken houses so that they, like you, can take custody &amp;#8212; not possession, but custody &amp;#8212; of Tyson&amp;#8217;s chicks, feed them, rear them, assume losses from those that fail to thrive, and in the end earn just enough money to service their endless debt, and realize a profit of perhaps $12K a year. Your bank thanks you; Tyson thanks you; George W. Bush thanks you; and I thank you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can continue sending your sons to die in Iraq on a fool&amp;#8217;s errand. When you bury them, you can console yourselves with Bush&amp;#8217;s platitudes about their heroic mission to defend America from weapons of mass destruction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can savor the deficit spending that stimulates commerce today, but will cripple the US economy in ten or fifteen years&amp;#8217; time when the bills come due with interest. Perhaps a Democrat will be in office at that time, who can be blamed for W&amp;#8217;s delayed economic fiasco.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can continue believing, as Republican Party brainwashing has persuaded you, that we, your neighbors, are your enemies. You can believe that we have no morals; that we pimp out our teenage daughters for Internet porn; that we eat babies; that we are all gay; that we are cowards on the battlefield; and that we want to run your lives and give you AIDS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s a clue: we are not your enemies; we are your countrymen. Your enemies are the greedy multinationals that the Republican Party bends over backwards to accommodate. Incidentally, most of them are based in Blue states, as are their Republican owners and major shareholders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here in the Blue States, Democrats and Republicans alike generate the lion&amp;#8217;s share of America&amp;#8217;s wealth, although it is you Reds who provide the lion&amp;#8217;s share of the stoop labor. You are our Mexicans, so to speak. We could not have accomplished the economic miracle that is America without your willing capitulation to a system that lies to you and fucks you over at every turn.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look at economic output and educational achievement on a state-by-state basis: it&amp;#8217;s painfully evident that we Blues are immensely more productive and better educated than you Reds. We have lots more money. We live longer. We eat better. We work less. We fuck more. We do cocaine and smoke fine Canadian buds, not the homebrew crank and cheap Mexican headache reefer you guys are stuck with. We drink French wine and Stoli martinis, not Budweiser. Our children rarely bother us: we&amp;#8217;ve got them on Ritalin and Prozac. Our teeth are straighter and whiter, our necks longer, and our fingernails cleaner. And many of us are the Republican elite who have just punked you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s good to be a Blue, regardless of which party you join.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understandably, you resent us, so you&amp;#8217;ve fabricated an imaginary measure of superiority: Christian &amp;#8220;values.&amp;#8221; Yet you talk about values the way a pre-teen girl talks about &amp;#8220;love&amp;#8221; in fan letters to Ashton Kutcher. You recycle quasi-religious platitudes and received slogans. You know nothing of moral theology, a rigorous philosophical pursuit that hardly exists outside the Catholic Church and its elite universities. You make of the Bible what you will; you attend prayer meetings with other semi-literates, where you reinforce each other&amp;#8217;s sloppy understandings of the text, and combine them with half-digested bits of old-timey Hallmark-card &amp;#8220;wisdom.&amp;#8221; And when you spout gibberish, you call it &amp;#8220;speaking in tongues.&amp;#8221; You actually fancy that you&amp;#8217;re saints, you silly, narcissistic creatures.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, you are fellow Americans. The Blue Republican elite encouraged you to vote for George W Bush, because they quite simply own him, and they know that his administration will make policies that help them, even if hurt you. We Blue Democrats voted for John Kerry because we believed he would minister to your needs better than Bush. A President Kerry would have shared some of our wealth with you, assured your health care, raised the minimum wage, and checked the rapacious greed of the multinationals that hold you in thrall.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;President Kerry would have helped us to help you, which is all that we ask. It pains us to see you in wage slavery. It pains us to see you so ignorant and uneducated, and so eager to place yourselves in bondage. Yes, we live better; but we wish you to live better too, even if it means sacrifice on our part.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What we wanted for you would have been far better than that which you, in your ignorant pride, demanded for yourselves. Oh, you defeated us all right, but only to your detriment.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We Blues will come out of the Bush era no worse for wear, although you Reds will come out very much diminished, deeper in debt, and less able to improve your circumstances by your own powers. But because you wish to be flattered more than helped, you will be grateful for your ass fucking from the Blue-state Republican elite that is laughing behind your backs today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We did not wish it so. We honestly did want to help.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On 2 November, you thanked us by electing a shrewd, manipulative handmaiden to corporate America who panders to you while ruthlessly exploiting your ignorance and weakness for the benefit of his patrons in the national plutocracy. There is nothing we can do about that. You won fair and square.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We should let you rot. We should secede and leave you to fend for yourselves. Then you will see firsthand just how dependent you are. We are sick of fighting for you by fighting against you. Perhaps, when you see how dreary your lives have become without us, you will finally develop the spine to fight for your basic, human rights. And then we will gladly confront the plutocracy alongside you. We need your help to defeat the Blue Republicans, who, I assure you, are just as decadent as we are, though often richer.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But until you finally learn to respect yourselves, we can&amp;#8217;t respect you, and we therefore can&amp;#8217;t be bothered to give a rat&amp;#8217;s ass about you.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;So let us secede, Blue America and Red America. We can handle the Blue state Republicans, so long as we don&amp;#8217;t have a lot of ignorant Red state lemmings frustrating our efforts and screwing themselves in the bargain. Secession will enable us both to live as we have chosen without the other&amp;#8217;s interference. We will prosper, and you will get a clue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But do stay in touch after the borders slam shut. When you finally tire of living on the modern, corporate plantations of Cargill, Tyson, ConAgra and Smithfield; when you tire of shopping at Wal-Mart and sending your daughters to sling hash at Denny&amp;#8217;s in hopes that they&amp;#8217;ll meet the nicer sort of truck driver; when you tire of sneaking into Blue America as illegal white-trash wetbacks eager for casual work dusting our parlors; and when, like men, you finally rise up in rebellion against this immoral usury &amp;#8212; then, and only then, let us talk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;#8217;ll gladly get your backs. But first you must grow the brains and the balls needed to profit from our help. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/2004/11/05/a-message-to-the-red-states</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/2004/11/05/a-message-to-the-red-states</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-11-05T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>freak out!</title>
                <description>&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/clusterfuck.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;clusterfuck&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/moogindigo.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;moog indigo&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/inc.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;in c&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Riley)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/10/25/freak-out</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/10/25/freak-out</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-10-25T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>new shit</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;wondershank&amp;#8221; is probably too high for me to sing properly, but you get the idea&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/wondershank.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;wondershank&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/ificouldsee.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;if i could see&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
wondershank

i've been standing outside
for thirteen months and thirteen days
i'm waiting 'till the time is right
to shut my mouth and turn and walk away

i don't know if you can hear me
i don't know if you still care
i can think of things i'd rather do
but here i am, still waiting for you

i'm walking by our favorite haunts
and looking out for signs of you
i tell myself it's easier this way
soon enough i'll believe myself, too

time is never kind to those who wish for it to pass
and i've been wishing for a long, long, long time


if i could see

sit still and i'll tell you a story
written in some other place or time
told by those who wanted to remember
an echo of a song sung, so sublime

if i could see far into the future
would i see the outcome of our lives?
those things that tied us two together
and the words that cut us up like knives

i guess this told me something
but the truth was more than i could face
you can't convince someone to love you
but i couldn't think of how to go on living until today

to my chagrin the story ends here
there is no happy ending to this tale
we choose the battles we engage in
there are some tests you pass and some you fail

for now i'll watch you sleeping
and tell my friends i didn't really care
we always hurt the ones we cherish
so why am i the one who has an ego to repair?
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/10/21/new-shit</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/10/21/new-shit</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>something new</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;so, now that i&amp;#8217;m formally studying again at suny purchase, i have lots more time to write, so hopefully i&amp;#8217;ll be able to update more often. this is a new tune that i&amp;#8217;m pretty happy with, although the track itself is kind of overproduced.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/icuffedyouadeliciousbass.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;i cuffed you a delicious bass&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
when i first saw your face, it was blurry and late
but i had a feeling that we would meet again
what i felt in my bones when we spoke on the phone
was akin to original sin

time it passed to slowly
but i was sure you were mostly
here for me

chorus:
i got less than i wanted
more than i bargained for
you watched me come in
now watch me walking out the door

they loved you in greenwich, despite your apprentice
standing with his face in his hands
despite his objections you made your connections
and now you're off to explore other lands

you said you'd always love him
well, until you had options
it was true

-chorus-

will you listen my dear, there is nothing to fear
you can trust me..as you would a friend
of course your friends are all men, so in thinking again
maybe to trust isn't all i intend

of course if you asked nicely
you know i'd get there precisely
right on time

-chorus-
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/09/24/something-new</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/09/24/something-new</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>a thought</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;i understand why “art music” exists. i understand absurdity, dadism, the need for a composer to express himself. i understand the contributions that esoteric music has made to the mainstream, and i have composed my share of avant garde pieces to explore this facet of musical creation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;but when i listen to your five minute atonal composition consisting of a
grand total of seven different sounds, don't tell me that the reason i don't like
it is because&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;i_dont_get_you&quot;&gt;i don’t get you&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if it’s not hard, then it’s not art. if you didn’t slave over it, then it’s just a byproduct of your quest for musical expression&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;musical_excrement&quot;&gt;MUSICAL EXCREMENT&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;but fortunately for you,&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;THAT doesn’t mean SHIT&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2004/09/24/a-thought</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2004/09/24/a-thought</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>studio ear</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;as i understand it, there is a semi-legitimate condition called, &amp;#8220;studio ear.&amp;#8221; basically, when you&amp;#8217;ve recorded and re-recorded a tune approximately 3 billion times, you start listening to and nitpicking every little thing. that definitely happened with the first two tunes i&amp;#8217;m posting today. i&amp;#8217;ve been working on these tunes for a couple of years, and they&amp;#8217;ve gone through several incarnations. i decided to post them because, especially in the case of &lt;i&gt;pathways&lt;/i&gt;, i&amp;#8217;m getting pretty sick of playing them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pathways.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;pathways&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/ghettoqueen.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;ghetto queen&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/ScatteredThoughts.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;scattered thoughts&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;&lt;p&gt;The third tune listed is a piano piece i wrote. it&amp;#8217;s probably going to end up split into two parts, to be played by two pianos. of course, finding &lt;span style='text-transform: none'&gt;Serious Pianists&amp;trade;&lt;/span&gt; that would want to play them is another issue altogether. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
She's got the funk that keeps me sleepless every single night
The way she talks, the way she walks, it's something I can't fight
I can't avoid the reaches of her thrilling urban scene
I close my eyes, and surrender to my Ghetto Queen

She moves to someone else's beat, she won't listen to my own
Sitting here just watching her brings pain I've never known
I'd like to think I'll move along and find someone for myself
But every time she cracks a smile I put my heart back on the shelf

Time will pass and friends will ask if I've seen her since that day
Since the time I stood with her and gave my heart away
I'll turn off all emotion, become like a cold machine
Just one more loss, but what a cost to the Ghetto Queen
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/02/15/studio-ear</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/02/15/studio-ear</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-02-15T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>some info</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a message from someone who was interested in pooking around InnerSpace today, and spent enough time providing some starter instructions that I figured I’d post them here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;thanks a lot for writing. i&amp;amp;#8217;m glad some people are checking this out&amp;amp;#8230;

right now the codebase isn&amp;amp;#8217;t really meant for public consumption. i do this primarily as a personal exercise, and although there are many parts of it that are very functional, other parts aren&amp;amp;#8217;t so refined&amp;amp;#8230;

i&amp;amp;#8217;ve attached a tarball, which contains some sparse documentation. i don&amp;amp;#8217;t know what your level of familiarity is with Python and the Twisted library (http://www.twistedmatrix.com), but some basic concepts from those areas can get you up and running.

First you&amp;amp;#8217;ll want to install Twisted if you don&amp;amp;#8217;t have it already, and run the setup.py script to install it in your python path.

then you&amp;amp;#8217;ll need to do the same with InnerSpace (python setup.py install) which should also build a JAR file of the client for you.

first build the server &amp;amp;#8220;TAP&amp;amp;#8221; file by running mktap innerspace
mktap supports some options, like specifying the port number, and SSL options, but for now it&amp;amp;#8217;s probably best to leave them as is.

then run the TAP file with twistd -nf innerspace.tap, which will run it in the foreground (removing the -n option daemonizes the server).

then, run the client with:
java -cp build/is-client.jar inner.space.client.Client

i believe the default u/p is phil/phil or wizard/wizard

besides &amp;amp;#8220;look&amp;amp;#8221;, there aren&amp;amp;#8217;t too many &amp;amp;#8220;real-world&amp;amp;#8221; verbs, as i&amp;amp;#8217;m working on the programming interface right now. @verb &amp;amp;lt;verb&amp;amp;gt; on &amp;amp;lt;obj&amp;amp;gt; will let you edit verb code, although i think most of the installed ones are predefined. However, this is functional enough to create new verbs, although the API for verbs is under heavy construction&amp;amp;#8230;you can also see the beginnings of the object editor with @edit &amp;amp;lt;obj&amp;amp;gt;

anyways, that&amp;amp;#8217;s about as much as i can tell you, for now. i&amp;amp;#8217;m not really providing any support for this project yet; it&amp;amp;#8217;s open-source for philosophical reasons, but i&amp;amp;#8217;m going to be the sole developer until i reach a certain point, and there&amp;amp;#8217;s no sense in me writing any serious documentation for it until the API is complete&amp;amp;#8230;

anyways, lots of luck! feel free to email me with any questions you might have, i&amp;amp;#8217;ll try to help you out whenever possible&amp;amp;#8230;

-phil&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2004/02/13/some-info</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2004/02/13/some-info</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-02-13T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>old stuff...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;i thought it might be nice to put up some really rough original drafts of some tunes that i&amp;#8217;ve done. most of these particular ones i haven&amp;#8217;t even recorded legitimately yet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;some of them are particularly hilarious because they feature larry&amp;#8217;s unique vocal stylings. sometimes i really think he&amp;#8217;s more suited to being a rock star than i am&amp;#8230;now if i could just get him to play an instrument&amp;#8230; ;-)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;OL&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/LotTrash.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;lot trash&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen/Hovish)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/Man-Tears.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;man tears&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen/Hovish)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/HarvestFriend.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;harvest friend&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt; (aka &lt;i&gt;harvest&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;small&gt; (Christensen/Hovish)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/Volcano.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Volcano&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen/Hovish)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/OL&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/02/01/old-stuff</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2004/02/01/old-stuff</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-02-01T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>the weblog formerly known as...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;so, although i did take some pleasure in my chosen title for this weblog, being the simpsons fanatic that i am, i decided that it sounds too much like some angsty goth kid's page of lamentations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;bubblehouse is relatively meaningless, except being the name of a &lt;a href='http://www.mmw.net'&gt;mmw&lt;/a&gt; tune that i like a lot. i also figure it's good to have the title be connected with the domain name.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;so i leave you with the following...&lt;BR /&gt;&lt;BR /&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Homer:&lt;/b&gt; What's wrong with you?  What are you trying to hide from me...
       [&lt;i&gt;Homer opens the door and sniffs&lt;/i&gt;]  What's that smell?  Onions...
       chili powder... cumin... juicy ground chuck?  It's chili!  Oh, my
       god, I'm missing the chili cook-off!  [&lt;i&gt;whining, fidgeting&lt;/i&gt;] I'm
       missing the cook-off, it's going on right now, and I'm missing 
       it.

&lt;b&gt;Marge:&lt;/b&gt; All right, I &lt;b&gt;was&lt;/b&gt; trying to keep it from you, but I had a good
       reason.  Every time you go to that cook-off you get drunk as a
       poet on payday.

&lt;em&gt;Marge asks him to remember last year.  In a flashback, we see an
obviously drunk Homer, a Duff in each hand, standing in the cotton-
candy machine.  &quot;Look at me...I'm a puffy pink cloud.&quot; he mumbles,
before he climbs out of the machine and lies on the ground, where dogs
lick at him.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Back to the present.  Homer is shuffling around in the closet.
&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Homer:&lt;/b&gt; Well of course, everything looks bad if you remember it.  Now
       where are my chili boots?
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2004/01/16/the-weblog-formerly-known-as</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2004/01/16/the-weblog-formerly-known-as</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>the game of life...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;it’s incredibly unusual for me to post this many times in a week, much less twice in a day, but&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when i added that emblem at the top, i got thinking about how i had never written a game of life program. this is one of those standard things all computer science students do at one point or another, but since i didn’t want to do things the standard way and had to drop my CS major, I never did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so, anyways, &lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/sandbox/Life/'&gt;check it out&lt;/a&gt;….&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/amf2yq==/2004/01/16/the-game-of-life</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/y29kaw5n/amf2yq==/2004/01/16/the-game-of-life</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>the privacy monsters</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;i really don’t like it when i have to fill out a form to download something. it doesn’t matter what the site asks for, or how much i want what they have to offer; i just don’t like being forced to fill out a form before i check their stuff out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;however, as a webmaster/musician, there comes a time when you’d like to see who it is that is really paying attention to your work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’ve set up my mp3s so that when you download them, you’re taken to a page where you can optionally fill out some information about yourself. it’s kind of like a less obnoxious version of a guestbook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;oh, and this is for my use only. it’s not going to be publicly posted, since things like that have a pretty large capacity for abuse. and if you do in fact want to leave your email address, you have my word that it won’t be resold or anything like that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so, if you would like to take the time to fill the form out, that’d be great, but if you have the same issues about them that i do, i understand. anyways, thanks for your time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/bxvzawm=/2004/01/15/the-privacy-monsters</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/bxvzawm=/2004/01/15/the-privacy-monsters</guid>
                <pubDate>2004-01-15T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>vocal tracking is hard</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;#8217;ve been trying to work on more tunes with vocal tracks, as vocals seem to be pretty much the hardest kind of &amp;#8220;instrument&amp;#8221; to record. then there&amp;#8217;s also the additional fact that while i don&amp;#8217;t &lt;i&gt;hate&lt;/i&gt; the sound of my own voice, i definitely feel uncomfortable listening to it. this is something i need to get over, and i guess there&amp;#8217;s only one way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I got a lot of help on this matter from the &lt;A href='http://www.tweakheadz.com/how_to_record_vocals.htm'&gt;TweakHeadz&lt;/A&gt; site. There&amp;#8217;s all kinds of good stuff on that site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;anyways, this tune is another one &lt;a href='http://www.livejournal.com/users/bataille'&gt;larry hovish&lt;/a&gt; and i collaborated on. we kinda were going for an alt-rock kind of feel, which i believe we suceeded in. furthermore, my solo in this tune has a nice crappy-neil-young quality to it. okay, that was not intentional, i was just sick of protools, and i didn&amp;#8217;t feel like doing it over again.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/ghosttrain.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ghost Train&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
On a ghost train to chicago
Smoke billows through the air
The only light that's seen at night
Comes from over here

On a ghost train to chicago
I've got no place to go
Got no place to be
won't you sit down with me

i ride this train every night
because i've got no soul
on an eastbound train to chicago
i left her looking out the door

on a ghost train to chicago
i smelled the sweet scent of her hair
she fell off the back; i looked down the track
in the middle of nowhere

On a ghost train to chicago
Smoke billows through the air
The only light that's seen at night
Comes from over here
&lt;/pre&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/12/27/vocal-tracking-is-hard</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/12/27/vocal-tracking-is-hard</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>mastering issues</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;it’s funny…i read an article last night about how people new to mastering tend to over-do the bass end when mastering, typically putting too much boost on the super-low frequencies, and not the low frequencies that our ears hear the most of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;well, anyone who’s downloaded a copy of Atmospheres, be careful listening to it at higher volumes, especially if you have any bass bost on already. i nearly blew out the speakers in my car when i first tried to listen to it. ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyways, i hope to have a newly mastered version of it up in a day or two&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;UPDATE: man, i never did that, did i? oh well&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/12/26/mastering-issues</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/12/26/mastering-issues</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-12-26T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>some updates...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So, as it&amp;#8217;s been awhile since I&amp;#8217;ve updated, I have lots of new developments. I&amp;#8217;ve been fortunate to find some time to tinker with IS, and there&amp;#8217;s lots of cool stuff coming along. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also removed the CVS directory from sourceforge, as I wasn&amp;#8217;t using it, since I prefer to use my own repository for now. Once I get to a releasable 1.0 candidate, I may mirror my repository to sf, but for now you can access the bubblehouse web-repository using the links to the left. I will eventually open up pserver access through my firewall, but until i get some more interest in this I&amp;#8217;m not going to bother.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oh, and I&amp;#8217;ve also started adding some unit-testing, using python&amp;#8217;s unittest modules. I&amp;#8217;m quickly becoming a believer in unit-testing, since I found a slew of bugs in the parser and registry (the only two tests i&amp;#8217;ve made yet). I will need to make a unit-test for the entity.py behemoth, but i&amp;#8217;m probably going to hold off until I implement ACLs for permissions instead of the &amp;#8220;rwx&amp;#8221; business, which will probably happen in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can read the rest of this entry for more details, but the improvements/changes include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;UL&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Licensing - now under the GPL&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Parser - all new parser engine&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Verbs - enhanced developer functionality&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Plugins - support for new &amp;#8220;core&amp;#8221; packages&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Observations - dynamic observations engine for different clients&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Security - ideas on a secure environment for verb authors&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;LI&gt;Build System - building and installation of client and server packages&lt;/LI&gt;
&lt;/UL&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Licenses&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After much hemming and hawing, I&amp;#8217;ve decided to license InnerSpace under the &lt;A HREF='http://www.gnu.org/licenses/gpl.html'&gt;GNU Public License&lt;/A&gt;. There&amp;#8217;s been a lot of talk around the GPL lately, what with &lt;A href='http://www.sco.com'&gt;SCO Group&lt;/A&gt;&amp;#8217;s &lt;A HREF='http://slashdot.org/search.pl?topic=88'&gt;relentless lawsuits and subpoenas&lt;/A&gt;, and a number of groklaw pundits have convinced me, at least, that the GPL is a viable extension of copyright law. I&amp;#8217;m not one of those people that&amp;#8217;s super concerned about this kind of stuff usually, but I&amp;#8217;ve been working on this project for a long time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Parser&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve revamped the parser, and it&amp;#8217;s a hundred times better. Previously, all sentences/commands had to be of the (BNF) form:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;verb[[ object-specifier] direct-object[ preposition[ object-specifier] object-of-the-preposition]]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This sucked for a couple of reasons. In addition to the actual style of the sentences being rather limited, you were also limited to one preposition-object pair. The new parser form is:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;tt&gt;verb[[[ object-specifier] direct-object]+[ preposition[ object-specifier] object-of-the-preposition]*]&lt;/tt&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I might be mixing up my BNF with RegEx, but basically what this comes down to is that you can now write verbs that support multiple preposition-object pairs (&amp;#8220;take the coal from the fire with the tongs&amp;#8221;), as well as skipping the direct object entirely (&amp;#8220;look at phil&amp;#8221;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Verbs&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The changes in the parser required some changes at the verb level, but they are few, and add some nice time-saving elements to verb authors.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;First of all, the &amp;#8220;vargs&amp;#8221; verb attribute will be going away soon, though it was never really used anyways. The code editor on the client will also no longer present those fields as options (additionally, I&amp;#8217;ve borrowed the jEdit text pane, which was placed into the public domain, to use inside the verb editor. It&amp;#8217;s a big improvement).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The replacement for the functionality that &amp;#8220;vargs&amp;#8221; was supposed to provide will be provided by new functions in the verb environment, called get&lt;em&gt;dobj, get&lt;/em&gt;pobj, has&lt;em&gt;dobj, has&lt;/em&gt;pobj, and their string equivalents, get&lt;em&gt;dobj&lt;/em&gt;str, etc&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the &amp;#8220;get&lt;em&gt;&amp;#8221; functions, if that object was not found, or that string was not used in the sentence, a NoSuchObjectError will be thrown. Also, as get&lt;/em&gt;pobj requires a preposition argument, possibly a NoSuchPrepositionError will be thrown, if the preposition given was not used in the sentence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, this still leaves open the problem of what to do if someone tries to use a player to do something, i.e., there&amp;#8217;s a verb &amp;#8220;kill&amp;#8221; on a player called &amp;#8220;wizard&amp;#8221;, at this point, another player could say &amp;#8220;kill phil with wizard&amp;#8221;. This might be alleviated with the rwx bits on a verb, or rather, by adding another bit. More likely is that the &amp;#8220;rwx&amp;#8221; Unix-type permissions system will be repalced by ACLs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to implement a system for delaying events, using the twisted deferred system. Since deferreds already run as part of the reactor event loop, i think it could be added in relatively easily&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Plugins&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is now possible to subclass inner.space.entity.Verb, which I&amp;#8217;m using to write the most basic verbs, such as Look, Emote, Say, etc&amp;#8230;as well as some programmer-oriented ones. The cool thing about this is that all of these verbs are installed by dropping a twisted-plugin-based package into your PYTHONPATH. This would make it easier for third parties to distribute new core packages (kinda like LambdaMOO has LambdaCore and JHCore, and others). When subclassing a verb, authors override execute() and use the object passed in to access variables from the parser.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Observations&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current system for controlling what the &amp;#8220;client&amp;#8221; sees is hard-coded to send a number of attributes from the object. I&amp;#8217;m going to change this so that if the object defines a verb called &amp;#8220;get_observations&amp;#8221;, that is called, and the result (presumably a hashtable) is sent to the client. If there is no verb defined, then the system object (#0) is checked for a verb with the same name that is passed an entity and the client object requesting it as arguments. I&amp;#8217;m not sure if there will be a default after this, or if it will be required that the system object supports that verb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Security&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my last post, I discussed ideas for a restricted execution enviroment. Since then I had a couple of talks with glyph about the idea, and he brought up some good points, that made me realize it&amp;#8217;s truly difficult to allow totally untrusted code to run safely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I realized long ago that one of the biggest issues to deal with is infinite recursion/looping, either with memory constraints, or infinite process spawning. A solution to this is to use the memory/process constraints placed on individual processes by the POSIX environment, i.e., forking processes for each verb. A prior version of InnerSpace attempted this, but had no simple way to provide interaction with the parent process.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of my ideas is that, in combination with my &lt;A href='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/viewcvs.cgi/*checkout*/SaferPython/safer.py?content-type=text/plain'&gt;
SaferPython&lt;/A&gt; module, I could create a transaction-based verb environment. Hopefully to the coder, it would be relatively unintrusive, but basically we trust that if the parent process receives a transaction list from the child, then we know that there was no ouroboros action going on.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;One thing that is really fruitless is keeping people who are really determined to hack the server from doing so. I mean the kind of people who are willing to overflow buffers in Python&amp;#8217;s unicode handling, etc. I think it&amp;#8217;s just as likely that an exploit could be found in any other aspect of the codebase.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think that the combination of forking, transactions, and restricted environments could provide a safe environment for generally untrusted, but registered users of the system.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;Build System&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, I&amp;#8217;ve begun using distutils to provide a means for installing the server packages, and creating a JAR for the java client. Also, I have rudimentary support built-in for building a MacOS X double-clickable application. Right now, during build it asks you for a classpath to your TwistedJava.jar file, since hardcoding class paths into the Info.plist file seems to be the only way to access code outside the package.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also, at the moment I am distributing a copy of the JavaApplicationStub binary which needs to be copied into the bundle for it to work. This is almost certainly illegal. I&amp;#8217;m hoping that until I figure out a solution, Apple doesn&amp;#8217;t sue me over 51 bytes of binary.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h3&gt;In conclusion&amp;#8230;&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyways, that&amp;#8217;s pretty much everything for now. I&amp;#8217;m trying really hard to keep everything updated, but this is the part of the process I hate the most, i.e., the documentation. I have to work on that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/12/22/some-updates</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/12/22/some-updates</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-12-22T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>a confession...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;sometimes i go back and change dates of blog entries to make it look like i update my site more frequently than i do. the last three entries were all written on the same day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;sigh&amp;gt;…that feels better&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/12/19/a-confession</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/12/19/a-confession</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>rocking junk</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;#8217;ve finally gotten a ProTools setup, after nearly two years of saying i was going to do it. My primary reason for doing so is that I&amp;#8217;m applying to &lt;a href='http://www.purchase.edu'&gt;Purchase&lt;/a&gt; for the third time, and I needed to be able to put in some serious time behind the mike (or in my case, &lt;a href='http://www.amplitube.com'&gt;amp-modelling software pre-amp&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had all these grand plans of getting this serious system, originally a &lt;A href='http://www.digidesign.com/products/digi002/'&gt;Digi 002&lt;/A&gt;, or a &lt;a href='http://www.motu.com/english/motuaudio/896/'&gt;motu 896HD&lt;/a&gt;, but although &lt;a href='http://www.rescuecom.com'&gt;my new job&lt;/a&gt; affords me some excess of cash (at least, compared to the days of unemployment benefits), i still wasn&amp;#8217;t going to be able to get something like that in time for the auditions. I settled on the &lt;A href='http://www.digidesign.com/products/mbox/'&gt;mbox&lt;/A&gt;, which only has two inputs, but they&amp;#8217;re pretty high-quality, and since i overdub everything anyways, it&amp;#8217;s working out.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve also been using some royalty-free samples I got my hands around, and it&amp;#8217;s made my life much easier in the drum-sound department. This has, however, lent a distinct electronic/industrial flavor to some of my tunes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;#8217;s the latest crop of compositions:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/Atmospheres.mp3'&gt;&lt;I&gt;Atmospheres&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sample.mp3'&gt;&lt;I&gt;sample&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/light.mp3'&gt;&lt;I&gt;light&lt;/I&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;small&gt; (Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/12/17/rocking-junk</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/12/17/rocking-junk</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>protools nonsense</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;These are a series of tunes that I put together with the assistance of &lt;a href='http://bubblehouse.org/~joel'&gt;joel bouchard&lt;/a&gt; and his protools rig. We were just learning how to use the thing &amp;mdash; for two weeks we drove ourselves crazy figuring out all its little idiosyncrasies. These are the fruits of our labor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/elfago.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;el-fago&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/misterblah.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mr. Something-Something&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/psuede.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;psuede&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen/Bouchard)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/pathways.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;pathways&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/harvest.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;harvest&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen/Hovish)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/untitled.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;a rock song&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/rivieraparadise.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Riviera Paradise&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Vaughan)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/10/13/protools-nonsense</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/10/13/protools-nonsense</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Nice New Things</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So right away I have something to show anyone who wants to look. I&amp;#8217;ve been thinking about the whole RExec/Bastion problem, and I may have come up with a solution. I&amp;#8217;d also certainly appreciate it if anyone could fill me in with any obvious security flaws&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Check out &lt;A HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/viewcvs.cgi/*checkout*/SaferPython/safer.py?content-type=text/plain'&gt;SaferPython&lt;/A&gt;. It is my attempt to rewrite a restricted environment for Python. Admittedly, I don&amp;#8217;t think I know enough about the new language features to be sure if this works. I&amp;#8217;ve tried a number of &amp;#8220;exploits&amp;#8221;, and this seems to provide the kind of protection &lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt; want, but I&amp;#8217;m pretty sure it doesn&amp;#8217;t have the abilities that some RExec users need.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I wrote this based upon the following premises:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;That my primary goal is to offer some sort of scripting enviroment, even if it is only a subset of the Python language. Call it PythonScript or something (ah, jk, I think that already exists)&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;That any class/object that I could want in the restricted environment would be accessible to me ahead of time.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;That none of the objects in this environment can return anything but safe objects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the moment, I can be sure the the classes are secure, since importing is disabled from inside the environment. Only classes/objects that are imported explicitly are available.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The way you&amp;#8217;d use it would be something like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
from safer import *
import string

# defaults to using the NameChecker class for permissions
env = Armory()
# we insert objects that we want to access, including any modules
# or built-in functions
env.insert('string', string) #the string module
env.insert('str', str)       #the str() built-in/type

# we can also specify other IPermission implementations
class myClass(object):
    pass
env.insert('MyClass', MyClass, ClassProtection)

env.r_exec(someUntrustedCode)
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The manual insertion of &lt;em&gt;ALL&lt;/em&gt; language objects is a bit of a pain, but this can be automated once I figure out what classes/objects are 100% safe for this environment. Although there is support for creating new instances of protected (Shielded) class objects, they are currently returned unrestricted. I&amp;#8217;m planning on fixing this once I figure out a nice way to do it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/09/24/nice-new-things</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/09/24/nice-new-things</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-09-24T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Ch-ch-ch-ch-changes...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;First of all, welcome to the latest-greatest version of the InnerSpace website. Since I slacked off so much on updating recently, I decided to start using Moveable Type to make a weblog for this site. Considering it greatly simplifies the process for me, I hope to be able to post more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have a bit more time to talk about some of the changes going on in the InnerSpace codebase. One of the biggest things has to do with some problems with Python 2.0.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the creation of Python 2.0, it was discovered that new class features break the RExec and Bastion modules. They no longer provide true security from untrusted code. This is obviously a big deal, since this is something projects like InnerSpace (including the Grail web browser, and, to some extent, the Zope project) rely on heavily. Some additional explanation of the situation can be found &lt;A HREF='http://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-dev/2002-December/031160.html'&gt;here&lt;/A&gt; and &lt;A HREF='http://mail.python.org/pipermail/python-dev/2003-January/031848.html'&gt;here&lt;/A&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, PythonLabs has pretty much said they have neither the resources to fix what&amp;#8217;s wrong with RExec/Bastion, nor the ability to provide a new solution. So, this kinda sucks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the moment, I have removed the restricted execution code (Python 2.3 won&amp;#8217;t even let you load the module), and verb code now gets executed &amp;#8220;straight up.&amp;#8221; This means you probably won&amp;#8217;t want to count on allowing free programmer rights until this gets fixed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I&amp;#8217;ve decided to drop the verb forking support until either I think of a better way to do it, or completely restructure InnerSpace again (man, I really don&amp;#8217;t want THAT to happen)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A little lesson on forking processes for anyone interested. Python has a builtin system function called fork(). fork() returns a integer that indicates the process ID of the child. Where things get weird is that the code after your fork call gets executed both in the child and in the parent. The integer you get from fork in the child is actually 0, so you want to do something like this:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;pre&gt;
import os

pid = os.fork()
if(pid):
    # the parent executes the stuff here
else:
    # and the child executes the stuff here
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;p&gt;The catch-22 with all this neat forking stuff is that although you have no problems reading variables in the child, modifying them doesn&amp;#8217;t really do any good. My solution to this was to have each child open a socket to the parent and use a custom protocol to modify the data in the parent when it changed in the child.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Basically, I was using a remote object mechanism (first PyRO, and then my own home-brewed solution) to give code running in a sub-process access to game runtime objects (remember, the goal was to allow nearly transparent access to these objects). This ended up being rather inelegant, since although all of the objects in the child would work as remote references to objects in the parent, what do you do when someone calls &lt;tt&gt;obj.list.append(somedata)&lt;/tt&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, those are the two major (bad) changes to InnerSpace since I last updated this page. In my next post I&amp;#8217;ll talk about some of the really cool changes that I&amp;#8217;ve touched on before.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/09/23/ch-ch-ch-ch-changes</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/09/23/ch-ch-ch-ch-changes</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Whoa! That's a Spicy Meatball!!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;#8217;s been a pretty long time since i&amp;#8217;ve updated anything on this page. This is, however, no indication of work being done on InnerSpace; as a matter of fact, things are better than ever!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been restructuring some of the less stable components of the framework, namely, the network layer. I&amp;#8217;ve opted to use the &lt;A HREF='http://www.twistedmatrix.com'&gt;Twisted framework&lt;/A&gt; to provide a networking layer. This allows me to focus on the stuff that&amp;#8217;s important for a framework like this, while having the assurance of a rock-solid networking foundation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As of yet, I haven&amp;#8217;t updated the CVS repository with the new stuff &amp;#8212; this is definitely on the way. I&amp;#8217;m under some time restraints, as I finally have a job, and that&amp;#8217;s taking up a lot of my time. However, here are some things you can look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; A new and nicer client, which provides some facilities for nicer text, embedded images, and a generally nicer (and more functional) experience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; A fully operational verb/object and property editor.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; A much more efficient networking layer (thanks to &lt;a href='http://www.twistedmatrix.com'&gt;Twisted&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; and much more&amp;#8230;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/09/21/whoa-thats-a-spicy-meatball</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2003/09/21/whoa-thats-a-spicy-meatball</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-09-21T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>tunes for enjoyment</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;P&gt;These are some recordings that I put together with matt cole (drums) and rob pawlings (bass). We had a short-lived project called &lt;i&gt;sesshomaru&lt;/i&gt; that we had a lot of fun doing, even though we really didn&amp;#8217;t have the time to do anything productive with it. We&amp;#8217;ll see what comes of it all&amp;#8230;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sesshomaru/redbaron.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Red Baron&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Cobham)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sesshomaru/freejazz.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Free Jazz for &amp;#8216;Heads&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; =&amp;gt;  &lt;small&gt;(sesshomaru)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sesshomaru/agogo.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;A Go-Go&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Scofield)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sesshomaru/bluebossa.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Blue Bossa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Dorham)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sesshomaru/allblues.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;All Blues&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Davis)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sesshomaru/dizshorn.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Who Stepped on Diz&amp;#8217;s Horn&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Christensen/Wilson)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/cgi-bin/download.cgi/sesshomaru/cissystrut.mp3'&gt;&lt;i&gt;Cissy Strut&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;small&gt;(Modeliste)&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/09/19/tunes-for-enjoyment</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/bxvzawm=/dhvuzxm=/2003/09/19/tunes-for-enjoyment</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-09-19T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>IT was a long, strange trip</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;i love to drive. i really do. the thought of driving 14 hours to see one of my favorite bands was not a strange one for me; i had done it on several occasions in the past, and been very glad i did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we left Old Forge, NY at 6:30AM on friday morning. we had wanted to leave earlier, but some of the crew had to work late, and this was decided to be the best time. the gates opened at 8:00AM, but the shows wouldn’t begin until saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;additionally, rather than taking the highway route down I-90 to I-95 to Maine, we took Route 2 across Vermont, New Hampshire, and much of Maine. this seemed more direct.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;along the way we encountered a few traffic issues, but we still arrived in the Limestone, ME area around 8:30PM. at this point, we ran into a traffic jam, but this was expected. we figured we probably had a 4-6 hour wait to get in, annoying, but tolerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16 and 1/2 hours later, we parked on the airfield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;you might wonder why we would do this to ourselves. “who the hell would wait in line for 16 hours to see a band?!?!” of course, we really had no choice. although we could have turned around an arrived home before we actually got in, we had all spent $150 to go, and driven a long way; we were there for good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in truth, we didn’t know how long we were going to be waiting. we expected some wait, and due to a change in course we took a different route in than the other Limestone veterans had taken before, we didn’t know how far away we actually were from the venue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we were about 13 miles away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;B&gt;finally there...&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;p&gt;after finally getting in and situated, we really didn’t have time for naps or anything, but we were glad to have lucked out with our campsite. we were about as close to the concert field as we could hope to be, and unlike some of our friends who we had talked to before cell phone use became impossible (70,000 cell-phone loving phans have that effect on a cell tower), we were able to camp on grass (instead of tarmack) and next to our cars (instead of a different lot).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;we were concerned about the whether, but it had already done all the damage it was going to do. torrential downpours in the previous week had turned many of the camping areas to muck, so they needed to be relocated. it was mostly sunny, and very pleasant at night.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;B&gt;tripping the light fantastic...&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;p&gt;refreshments (chemical and otherwise) were abundant, and we really didn’t have to go anywhere to find anything; it all came to us. i really don’t know how some people had the energy to consume all the recreational products that they did, considering that after 30 hours in the car, and pretty high heat and humidity all day, i felt like a dishrag. the last thing i needed was to be in a chemical funk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;FONT FACE='Helvetica, Arial'&gt;
&lt;B&gt;08/02/03 Loring Air Force Base, Limestone, ME&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;I&gt;First set was 1h50m!!!&lt;/I&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Set I:&lt;/B&gt; AC/DC Bag,  Ya Mar&gt;  Runaway Jim,  Reba,  Birds of a Feather,  Meatstick,  Two Versions of Me,  Vultures,  Limb By Limb,  Cavern
&lt;B&gt;Set II:&lt;/B&gt; Down With Disease&gt;  NICU,  Brother,  Lawn Boy,  Discern,  Waves,  David Bowie
&lt;B&gt;Set III:&lt;/B&gt; Rock and Roll&gt;  Seven Below,  Scents and Subtle Sounds&gt;  Spread It Round,  Bug
&lt;B&gt;Encore:&lt;/B&gt; Dog Log,  The Mango Song
&lt;/FONT&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this Ya Mar was 17 minutes long. instead of the usual solos over the chord changes, it just went into outer space. after about 15 minutes, i had to ask joel what song it was, since i had totally forgotten (plus i couldn’t believe that they could take Ya Mar to the places they did!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;some phans apparently were chanting meatstick, and the band opted to play this, instead of the Fluffhead that everyone had wanted to hear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;FONT FACE='Helvetica, Arial'&gt;
&lt;B&gt;08/03/03 Loring Air Force Base, Limestone, ME&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Set I:&lt;/B&gt; Daniel,  Saw it Again,  Punch You in the Eye,  Army of One,  Chalkdust Torture,  Wilson,  Mike's Song&gt;  I Am Hydrogen&gt;  Weekapaug Groove
&lt;B&gt;Set II:&lt;/B&gt; Mellow Mood,  Ghost,  Mist,  Pebbles and Marbles,  You Enjoy Myself&gt;  Chariots of Fire,  Loving Cup
&lt;B&gt;Set III:&lt;/B&gt; 46 Days,  Julius,  The Lizards,  Secret Smile,  Run Like An Antelope
&lt;B&gt;Encore:&lt;/B&gt; Good Times Bad Times
&lt;/FONT&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a verse got lost in Wilson somewhere, and they just ended it, prompting trey to say Wilson was the shortest version ever, and was “postable”, after which he made a keyboard typing motion with both hands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then after the entire crowd got on the Fluffhead chant bandwagon, trey asked mike, but “mike said no”. i think they pretty much all realized they hadn’t practiced it enough to risk ruining the neat perfect shows they had played so far. they ripped out on a Mike’s Groove instead, tho.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;finally, instead of the “rye, rye, rocco” part of Antelope, Trey said his little goodbye message to everyone, and promised a “traffic-free festival” for next time, whatever that means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;B&gt;let's get the FUCK OUT!!!&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;p&gt;we were ready to hit the road at 10:30AM the next morning, and since there seemed to be so many people leaving that night, we figured we’d have no problems getting out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it took 10 and 1/2 hours to get out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;total concert time: ~45.5 hours total car time: ~55.5 hours&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;B&gt;in conclusion...&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tucker and i decided on the best way to describe this festival. it was an ice cream sandwich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it looks so good, and you can’t wait to eat it. then, salivating, you take a bite, only to discover that the outside part is made of dirt, and it’s twice as thick as the ice cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but the ice cream is so sweet, you almost forget about the fact the you just ate dirt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;almost.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cghpc2g=/bxvzawm=/2003/08/07/it-was-a-long-strange-trip</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cghpc2g=/bxvzawm=/2003/08/07/it-was-a-long-strange-trip</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-08-07T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Burgettstown Warmup</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;man, what a show&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i couldn’t believe my good luck to see this show. i barely made it; i had a really good job interview in manhattan on thursday, and was so sure i was going to need to make a day trip down there that i almost didn’t go to PA. of course, i didn’t get the job, but before i knew that i decided it was important for me to go to this show.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;when this setlist first started coming up on &lt;A HREF='http://www.therhombus.com/forums'&gt;the rhombus&lt;/A&gt;, a number of people surmised it was a fake. never before had phish busted out with so many rare tunes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;FONT FACE='Helvetica, Arial'&gt;
&lt;B&gt;07/29/03 Post Gazette Pavilion, Burgettstown, PA&lt;/B&gt;
&lt;B&gt;Set I:&lt;/B&gt; Daniel Saw the Stone,  Camel Walk,  Gotta Jibboo,  Cool it Down,  Scent of a Mule,  Fee&gt;  Timber&gt;  When the Circus Comes to Town,  McGrupp and the Watchful Hosemasters,  Golgi Apparatus
&lt;B&gt;Set II:&lt;/B&gt; Crosseyed and Painless&gt;  Thunderhead,  Brother,  Harpua&gt;  Bittersweet Motel,  Harpua,  I Fooled Around and Fell in Love&gt;  HYHU&gt;  Harpua,  David Bowie
&lt;B&gt;Encore:&lt;/B&gt; Farmhouse
&lt;/FONT&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this was the first time i got to see Camel Walk, Scent of a Mule, Fee, McGrupp, Brother, and Harpua, all tunes i had wanted to see for a long time, and all at one show!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what a fine warmup for IT!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cghpc2g=/bxvzawm=/2003/07/31/burgettstown-warmup</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cghpc2g=/bxvzawm=/2003/07/31/burgettstown-warmup</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-07-31T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>workin' for the man</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;i had the beginnings of the interview process today with &lt;B&gt;american express financial advisors&lt;/B&gt;. i’m rather torn over what to think about it, because it’s not the kind of job i ever imagined myself doing. it’s basically very much like a medical residency; you don’t get paid shit to start, but if you get through the first two-to-three years, you’ll be making around 100k.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’m not concerned about the money. it’s very exciting to think about making that much, but the part that kills me is that they told us straight out, “plan on working 60-65 hours a week for the first two years.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i really don’t like working, and i especially don’t like working 10 hours a day, six days a week. furthermore, doing so will make it very difficult to work on my music, or even look for another job. i feel like i should take it just because i need a job so bad, but i just don’t think it’s going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;this is a career-type position, and it’s set-up with the idea that it’s only worth going through all the bullshit at first if you’re going to continue in the industry. i really don’t want to do this, because that means my career path will have to change from wanting to be in I.T., to being a financial advisor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and shit, who really works 60 hours a week anyways? i did that at american music for six weeks and it nearly killed me. granted, you’re making overtime, but sheeeit….&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;sigh&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/07/17/workin-for-the-man</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/07/17/workin-for-the-man</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>let's go phishin'</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;i&amp;#8217;m pretty stoked about &lt;a href='http://www.phish.com'&gt;phish&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8217;s evolution lately. it&amp;#8217;s kinda funny; they have so many side projects going on, and it just seems to make them better and more solid as a band. look at their latest show:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;7/15/03 West Valley Amphitheater, West Valley, UT
Set I:  AC/DC Bag,  Ya Mar,  Theme from the Bottom,  Saw it Again,  Poor Heart,  Two Versions of Me,  Secret Smile,  Mike&amp;amp;#8217;s Song&amp;gt;  I am Hydrogen&amp;gt;  Weekapaug Groove
Set II:  Mr. Completely&amp;gt;  Low Rider&amp;gt;  Big Black Furry Creature from Mars&amp;gt;  Buried Alive&amp;gt;  Big Black Furry Creature from Mars&amp;gt;  Ha Ha Ha&amp;gt;  Big Black Furry Creature from Mars&amp;gt;  Mr. Completely&amp;gt;  Spread It Round,  Walls of the Cave,  Golgi Apparatus,  Slave to the Traffic Light
Encore:  Sleeping Monkey&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i was blown away when i first saw Mr. Completely come up, since it&amp;#8217;s definitely one of my favorite trey band tunes. from there the set just went into outer space.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;which brings me to my next thought, which is whether i should try to go to the Burgettstown, PA show on the 29th. i&amp;#8217;m sure i could pick up a ticket on lot (there are many around on the extra ticket boards, and it may not even be sold out yet), but the issue that is going to decide this is primarily financial.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;i have a couple of job interviews coming up (one today, actually), and i&amp;#8217;m hoping i&amp;#8217;ll have a job within the next two weeks. if i don&amp;#8217;t, i&amp;#8217;ll pretty much have to move back in with my parents (seinfeld was right; there is nothing about moving back home that indicates that your life is going in the right direction). however, if that &lt;i&gt;does&lt;/i&gt; happen, i won&amp;#8217;t need to pay this coming month&amp;#8217;s rent, so i&amp;#8217;ll be a little richer from the unemployment cashish&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;i guess this is something i&amp;#8217;ll decide on the 28th&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cghpc2g=/bxvzawm=/2003/07/16/lets-go-phishin</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cghpc2g=/bxvzawm=/2003/07/16/lets-go-phishin</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-07-16T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>to blog or not to blog...</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;…that isn’t really a question, since it’s obvious what was my decision. i’m not sure if blogging is really for me, but i figure i’ll give it a try&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i tried &lt;A HREF='http://www.livejournal.com'&gt;LiveJournal&lt;/A&gt; for awhile, but i just didn’t like it. maybe it’s because i couldn’t think of anything to put it in. i figure running my own will let my customize it and maybe do some cool things. i’m not even sure what to focus on; probably music will be my focus, since that’s about all i care about. maybe occasional posts about other things i’m thinking. we’ll see&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one thing i don’t want is some stupid blog where i talk about shit that no one would ever want to read, which may be unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i really hate the word ‘blog.’&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/07/08/to-blog-or-not-to-blog</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/07/08/to-blog-or-not-to-blog</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>getting the fuck outta dodge</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;sometimes, i admire vagrants. syracuse seems to have quite a lot of them downtown. i guess i don’t think of this place as being that big, even though i guess it is. the truth is, nobody wants to be homeless, or otherwise forced to panhandle. but the prospect of only having one thing “to worry about” is alluring, at least in theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i’ve known various types of vagrants. there’s the most obvious kind, aka the bums. but there’s a few other variants, such as the lot trash that show up at every jamband concert, squatters in more metropolitan areas, or a more positive kind…maybe i’d call them hobos. the kind of person who drops everything and just decides to wander the earth (“like cain in kung-fu”).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i find the idea enticing, especially since i really feel like i’m only a few steps above hobodom myself, what with the unemployment and all. of course, i’d want to wander like that only if i had a big enough fund so i could not have to worry about eating and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but then again, i guess that’s the difference between hobo and traveler.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/07/08/getting-the-fuck-outta-dodge</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/cmfudhm=/2003/07/08/getting-the-fuck-outta-dodge</guid>
                <pubDate>2003-07-08T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Posterity Tarball</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;With this, the role of InnerSpace as my project for CSC436 has ended. Although I really didn’t get as far as I would have liked, IS is in a reasonably functional state. There is currently no documentation or even code comments, but that will be for another version. I’m still going to grant this release the title of &lt;A HREF='http://bubblehouse.org/innerspace/innerspace-0.5.tar.gz'&gt;innerspace-0.5&lt;/A&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2001/08/18/posterity-tarball</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2001/08/18/posterity-tarball</guid>
                <pubDate>2001-08-18T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Milestones</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple weeks ago, we came up with a milestone chart for the rest of the project. Now they&amp;#8217;re finally posted!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Milestone 1 06/24/01
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;b&gt;[Done]&lt;/b&gt; Add variables to executing verb’s namespace
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;b&gt;[Done]&lt;/b&gt; Execute verb code in child process
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;b&gt;[Done]&lt;/b&gt; Filter out remote stubs
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Milestone 2 07/08/01
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;b&gt;[Done]&lt;/b&gt; Allow for out of band commands in the client
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Implement GUI for object editing
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;
				&lt;b&gt;[Done]&lt;/b&gt; Implement Observation mechanism in objects
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Milestone 3 07/15/01
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Add convenience methods to environment
				&lt;ul&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;create/destroy objects
					&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;set/get property info
					&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;get user list
					&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;li&gt;get active task list/kill tasks/view task info
					&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;/ul&gt;
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Milestone 4 08/01/01
		&lt;ul&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Implement basic navigation
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Implement communication between players
			&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Rudimentary puzzles/areas
			&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2001/07/02/milestones</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2001/07/02/milestones</guid>
                <pubDate>2001-07-02T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>CSC436 at SUNY Oswego</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m going to be using InnerSpace as my project for Doug Lea’s &lt;A HREF='http://gee.cs.oswego.edu/dl/csc436/'&gt;Network Systems&lt;/A&gt; class at &lt;A HREF='http://www.oswego.edu'&gt;SUNY Oswego&lt;/A&gt;. This is good for a couple of reasons. First of all, it’ll motivate me to find more time to finish this thing that’s been on my back for so very long. Second, I’ll be working with &lt;A HREF='mailto:groberts_NO_@_SPAM_oswego.edu'&gt;Greg Roberts&lt;/A&gt;, who will provide a valuable perspective, since he’s fairly unfamiliar with Python and especially InnerSpace. He’ll be helping me write verbs for the game, which will serve to teach him Python, show me were things are difficult or confusing, and also locate the numerous bugs that are probably just waiting to pop out. Finally, I’ll have access to DL’s brain. &lt;i&gt;(&amp;quot;eeexcellent&amp;quot;)&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2001/06/01/csc436-at-suny-oswego</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2001/06/01/csc436-at-suny-oswego</guid>
                <pubDate>2001-06-01T00:00:00-04:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Introduction</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Hrm, well, where to begin? InnerSpace has been in the design process for four years now, and has been written and rewritten many, many times. Each time I always thought, “Oh, I’ve got everything figured out, so I should be finished Real Soon Now.” Ha!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;so_what_is_it&quot;&gt;So What Is It?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The buzzword-compliant description would be: InnerSpace is a text-based virtual reality framework that allows multiple Internet users to connect to, manipulate and aid in the creation of a limitless universe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, it’s a MUD, but it’s the best damn MUD out there!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/06/introduction</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/06/introduction</guid>
                <pubDate>2000-03-06T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Things MUDs Should Have</title>
                <description>&lt;ul&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;Authoring Support/Permissions Model&lt;/b&gt; - I wanted to be able to safely give any user programmer's rights, without having to worry about the havoc they could bring on the system.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;An Elegant Internal Programming Language&lt;/b&gt; - Initially, I was going to just embed a Python interpreter into my Java code, but I realized that Python's cool factor was just too great. So now the whole server is written in Python.
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;Better Object Referencing&lt;/b&gt; - Most MUDs suffer from issues with naming objects. There's basically two established methods; you either assign each object an arbitrary unique ID (LambdaMOO's method), or ensure that no two objects share the same name. These methods had various shortcomings. If each object had a unique ID number, you could allow the name property on various objects to be the same. However, the drawback was that if your player character was not physically in the same room as the object you wanted to refer to, you were forced to refer to it by it's ID, like #175847. Conversely, if each object has a unique internal name, you'd be able to refer to something like candle(4). However, for things to look less intrusive, you had to set a special property that would change the name users saw when they looked at an object. You then assigned an aliases property that would provide a number of other ways to refer to the object.&lt;br /&gt;
		My solution is nicer, I think. The inner.space.registry keeps track of all objects by name and ID. So for the most part, you just refer to objects by their name. But if there's more than one item with that name, an AmbiguousError is raised by the parser, which asks &quot;When you say, 'candle', do you mean candle (#456), candle (#726), or candle (#5)?&quot;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;
		&lt;b&gt;A Graphical Object Editor&lt;/b&gt; - So I may have come to appreciate UNIX, but I still love my Macintosh. By the same token, I want to be able to see at a glance all the major attributes of an object and be able to edit them easily.
	&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/05/things-muds-should-have</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/05/things-muds-should-have</guid>
                <pubDate>2000-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>So Much Code, So Little Time</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Really, there’s many things that I think make InnerSpace pretty cool. If you’re still with me at this point, you rock. Here’s some miscellaneous neat stuff:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All game objects (users, rooms, doors, etc.) are represented by one class. Any object can potentially be a container for other objects, though by default they are not. Objectshave a parent, which gets consulted if a selected property or verb isn’t found on the child.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Every command entered by the user forks a new process to run the code in. That way a malicious (or stupid) user can’t lock up the rest of the system, only it’s verb call.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The Pyro (PYthon Remote Objects) package is used to allow child processes access to the world’s objects. It’s been rather elegantly hacked (I think) to allow a sort of verification by remote code, so the (yet unwritten) object editor can be a little easier to write, while still being fairly secure.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;The InnerSpace client is still written in Java, which allows for easy distribution by applet or other platform-independent method.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/05/so-much-code-so-little-time</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/05/so-much-code-so-little-time</guid>
                <pubDate>2000-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>History</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Initially, this project started as a port of LambdaMOO to Java. Of course, I didn’t even get halfway through the first design without realizing a million things that were either A.) annoying design choices in LambdaMOO, or B.) practically impossible to implement in Java. I got pretty far, too, before I realized this (in fact, I still have the original version of InnerSpace written in Java using mucho RMI &amp;lt;shudder&amp;gt;). I realized that there were a number of things that I wanted to implement that other MUD/MOO/M* packages just didn’t. BTW, I’m going to use the phrase MUD from here on, even though it’s an oversimplification.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/05/history</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/aw5uzxjzcgfjzq==/y29kaw5n/2000/03/05/history</guid>
                <pubDate>2000-03-05T00:00:00-05:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
